<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tony Wolski</title><link>https://awolski.com/</link><description>Recent content on Tony Wolski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awolski.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>April 2020 Reflection</title><link>https://awolski.com/april-2020-reflection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/april-2020-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each month I go back over the notes in my bullet journal and pull out anything of significance: notes, quotes, patterns, lessons, achievements, things that have gone well and those that haven&amp;rsquo;t. I take what I learn and feed into the next month. It&amp;rsquo;s a ritual of continuous improvement, a cadence of accountability, that has served me well. In 2020 I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with publishing my reflection notes. Here&amp;rsquo;s what happened in April (and March) 2020.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Shape up</title><link>https://awolski.com/shape-up/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 05:39:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/shape-up/</guid><description>I just finished reading Shape Up by Ryan Singer of Basecamp. As a long time hater disliker of Agile and Scrum, Shape Up is a breath of fresh air, and in my opinion offers a realistic alternative to the industry standard way of working. It&amp;rsquo;s a great read and provides a detailed a look at how Basecamp work.
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to like about the book, and the process, so I thought I would pull out a few of the bits I appreciate and share them here.</description></item><item><title>Ten percent</title><link>https://awolski.com/10pc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:39:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/10pc/</guid><description>Each month I give 10% of my earnings (income not profit) to causes that benefit others and improve our long-term future.
I select charities recommended by organisations such as Effective Altruism and Give Well to maximise my donations and turn them into real action.
This page exists not to boast, but to hold myself accountable. It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation intention.
Why? I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly fortunate. I was born in a safe and prosperous country, raised by loving parents, siblings, extended family and friends.</description></item><item><title>Emergency fund</title><link>https://awolski.com/ef/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 05:39:10 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/ef/</guid><description>The COVID-19 pandemic has highlighted how important it is to have an emergency fund. It has also demonstrated how advantageous it is, and how easy it can be, to live simply and to be content with the basics. So much can be taken away so quickly, as we have all experienced in recent times, and the more changes we have to adapt to, the more difficult it is to do so.</description></item><item><title>TEDx Cardiff 2020</title><link>https://awolski.com/tedx-cardiff-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 11:46:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/tedx-cardiff-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was fortunate enough to be invited to &lt;a href="https://tedxcardiff.co.uk/">TEDx Cardiff 2020&lt;/a> on the weekend. I had never been to a TED event before, but having seen my fair share of TED talks (some of which have changed my life) I jumped at the chance to see one live.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The MCs for the day, &lt;a href="http://richardastrudwick.com/">Richard Strudwick&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://neilmonteiro.com">Neil Monteiro&lt;/a>, were engaging, knowledgeable and funny. They were a likable pair and had great chemistry, clearly built on the foundation of a good friendship. They bounced off each other in a way that reminded me of Australian radio and television comedic pair &lt;a href="https://www.hamishandandy.com/">Hamish and Andy&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>February 2020 Reflection</title><link>https://awolski.com/february-2020-reflection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/february-2020-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each month I go back over the notes in my bullet journal and pull out anything of significance: notes, quotes, patterns, lessons, achievements, things that have gone well and those that haven&amp;rsquo;t. I take what I learn and feed into the next month. It&amp;rsquo;s a ritual of continuous improvement, a cadence of accountability, that has served me well. In 2020 I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with publishing my reflection notes. Here&amp;rsquo;s what happened in February.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Choose freedom over loyalty</title><link>https://awolski.com/choose-freedom-over-loyalty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/choose-freedom-over-loyalty/</guid><description>&lt;p>Avoid loyalty cards. Avoid frequent flyer programs. Avoid any type of loyalty scheme, store cards or points systems. Why? Because they lock you in and take away your ability to choose the best option in the current situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An example. This morning I had a couple of hours to burn before I met with a friend. It was a beautiful day, the sun was out and my walk into town was an absolute joy. My plan was to while away the time reading a book, and I really wanted to do so in a coffee shop where the sun was blazing in. Instead I chose to go to a coffee shop where I had accumulated enough stamps on their loyalty card to get a free coffee. It was a nice, and I enjoyed my coffee, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t where I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> wanted to be. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t in the warmth of the sun.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My ability to choose the best option in the moment was affected by my loyalty to a particular chain, and the lure of a free coffee. Of course, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a free coffee. I had to buy nine before that to qualify for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fresh starts</title><link>https://awolski.com/fs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/fs/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love fresh starts. Blank pages, new notebooks. The start of a new football season. The start of a new week, month&amp;hellip; a new year. Fresh starts mean opportunity and possibility, optimism and clarity. They give you the chance to try something new, or go again with renewed vigour, taking with you the lessons you learned previously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Fresh starts give you energy. Which is why you should build more of them into your, more often.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used to love getting new notebooks at the start of a new school year. Each one gave me the chance to get things just right. Neat writing, straight lines, maybe even a new handwriting style. All the mistakes I made in previous notebooks were history. My mind would be full ideals and positivity about how well I would to do in the year ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I was always most motivated at the start of a football season. As difficult as preseasons were, finals aside, those were some of the most enjoyable months of the football year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Starting afresh gives us hope and opens us up to the possibilities of &lt;em>what could be&lt;/em>. It lets you reflect on the mistakes you made in the past, and allows you to design solutions so you don&amp;rsquo;t make the same mistakes again.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monzo webhooks to Google spreadsheets</title><link>https://awolski.com/monzo-to-gsheets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/monzo-to-gsheets/</guid><description>&lt;p>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve used Google spreadsheets to track my finances. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried using services like &lt;a href="https://www.moneydashboard.com/">Money Dashboard&lt;/a> in the past, but although they are simple to use, there is always a feature I want that is missing. I prefer to have control of my data so I can add functionality as and when I need it. So despite the setup and maintenance overhead, a spreadsheet is still the way to go in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I used to export bank and credit card transactions in csv format and import them manually. Doing so was a laborious and time consuming task which I hated, but writing scripts to automate it seemed like overkill, especially when authentication to Google and numerous banks was involved. Not to mention differences in export format between banks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Soon after I consolidated my accounts to &lt;a href="https://monzo.com/">Monzo&lt;/a> I realised they had an API, including webhooks. &lt;em>Transaction webhooks!&lt;/em> I pondered how easy it would be to push my transaction data to Google spreadsheets in &lt;em>real time&lt;/em>, eliminating the manual and time consuming process of exporting/importing them myself. I thought if transactions fed directly into my sheet automatically, all I would need to do is categorise them. Simple. I knew it was possible to create web applications GSheets with &lt;a href="">Apps Script&lt;/a>, so all the ingredients were there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After reading some documentation and hacking about for an hour or so I&amp;rsquo;d proven it was entirely possible. Now, when a transaction occurs in my Monzo account it appears in the finance spreadsheet within milliseconds. This post explains how I got it working.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DevOps</title><link>https://awolski.com/devops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/devops/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a &amp;lsquo;DevOps&amp;rsquo; engineer I often get asked &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;What is DevOps?&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Honestly, I struggle to answer. I usually come out with some spiel about automation and automating myself out of job. Which of course is next to impossible, which is why I don&amp;rsquo;t mind saying it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But really, what is DevOps?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>DevOps is a term that rose from the car crash that was Development and Operations working in silos. Colleagues batting for the same team, working towards the same goals, but at the same time, enemies, convinced of, and cursing, each other&amp;rsquo;s incompetence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>January 2020 Reflection</title><link>https://awolski.com/january-2020-reflection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/january-2020-reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each month I go back over the notes in my bullet journal and pull out anything of significance: notes, quotes, patterns, lessons, achievements, things that have gone well and those that haven&amp;rsquo;t. I take what I learn and feed into the next month. It&amp;rsquo;s a ritual of continuous improvement, a cadence of accountability, that has served me well. In 2020 I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with publishing my reflection notes. Here&amp;rsquo;s what happened in January.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cold showers</title><link>https://awolski.com/cold-showers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/cold-showers/</guid><description>&lt;p>I never thought I would say this, but here it is&amp;hellip; I love cold showers. Even in the middle of a cold UK winter, my days are so much better when I start them with an icy cold shower.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me rephrase that. I don&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em>love&lt;/em> cold showers. The moment before entry is not one of eagerness, and the moment after entry not one of pleasure. What I love about them is how they make me feel, both during, and in particular, after the shower. I can wake up feeling a bit off, or even downright pessimistic, but after a short breath work session and a cold shower I feel totally re-energised and ready to take on the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was introduced to breathe work and cold water therapy by a &lt;a href="https://control-alt-delete.net">friend of mine&lt;/a> when wild camping in the French Alps. On the way down the mountain he took me through a guided breath work session followed by cold water immersion. I&amp;rsquo;ve never felt water so cold in all my life, and although I didn&amp;rsquo;t last more than thirty seconds in the water, the pain in my hands, feet and forearms was so intense I never thought I would do it again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But at a breath workshop in London a few months later, which involved being immersed in an ice bath for two minutes, I realised I could control my experience of, and my reaction to, the icy cold water. I also felt amazing afterwards. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a cold shower morning routine.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2019 Reflections</title><link>https://awolski.com/2019-reflections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/2019-reflections/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started to do a 2019 reflection post and quickly realised it was blowing out to a huge post, so I decided to break it down into smaller bite size chunks, which I&amp;rsquo;ll add in the coming week.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2019 Reflections - Health</title><link>https://awolski.com/2019-reflections-health/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/2019-reflections-health/</guid><description>&lt;p>Having completed a &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/nice-70_3">70.3&lt;/a> in 2018, I started the year assuming I would do another big fitness challenge. Initially I landed on a marathon, but in the first few days of the year I ruled it out. Training for the 70.3, although enjoyable and addictive, was time consuming, and I wanted to direct my attention to other endeavours in 2019. On the 4th January my bullet journal reads:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Decision made. Marathon out. Full time work is just too much when your focus this year is building a brand.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I decided to try a simpler approach to exercise: to do something, even if it was only small, every day. 50 push ups, 30 pull ups, 15 minutes of yoga. Just try to not break the chain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In total I hit 289 days of exercise from a possible 365, a strike rate of 79%. I&amp;rsquo;m usually really tough on myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m disappointed I didn&amp;rsquo;t reach a round number like 300 days, or 80-90%. But viewed from different perspective I averaged over 5 ½ days per week, which is, in retrospect, a reasonable accomplishment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Irrespective of how many days I did, I hit the end of the year feeling fantastic. I felt strong &lt;em>enough&lt;/em>, fit &lt;em>enough&lt;/em> and flexible &lt;em>enough&lt;/em>. My focus was on the process and not the end result. I stopped comparing myself with others, how fast I could run compared to X, how much I could lift compared to Y, what I was doing or what I looked like compared to Z. It became all about putting an X down each day. The result? A much happier me, both physically and mentally.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artificial environments of scarcity</title><link>https://awolski.com/artificial-environments-of-scarcity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/artificial-environments-of-scarcity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In their book &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Millionaire-Next-Thomas-Stanley-Ph-D/dp/0671015206">&lt;em>The Millionaire Next Door&lt;/em>&lt;/a>, authors Thomas Stanley and William Danko discuss how millionaires who don&amp;rsquo;t budget become millionaires. These millionaires become wealthy because &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;They create an &lt;strong>artificial economic environment of scarcity&lt;/strong> for themselves and the other members of the household.&amp;quot;&lt;/em> In other words, they only make available to spend, by themselves and the members of their family, a proportion of the total amount of money earned. The rest is invested.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/">Cal Newport&lt;/a> is a father of three, a professor and successful author who produces peer reviewed articles and books, amongst other work, at a prodigious rate. He also doesn&amp;rsquo;t work after 5:30pm, which seems an impossible feat given how much he creates. In his book &lt;a href="https://www.calnewport.com/books/deep-work/">Deep Work&lt;/a> Newport outlines what he terms &lt;em>fixed-schedule productivity&lt;/em>, in which &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;I fix the firm goal of not working past a certain time, then work backwards to find productivity strategies that allow me to satisfy this declaration.&amp;quot;&lt;/em> It seems counterintuitive, but by limiting the time available for work he is able to focus and produce more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://minimalismfilm.com/">Minimalism&lt;/a> — &lt;em>A Documentary About the Important Stuff&lt;/em>, we see the growing trend of people downsizing to tiny houses. The motivation for living in smaller houses, smaller spaces, seems to be one of affordability, simplicity and sustainability. But regardless of the intent, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that people choosing to live in tiny houses are &lt;em>limiting&lt;/em> the space available in which to live and store their belongings. This in turn makes &amp;lsquo;space&amp;rsquo; available in other areas of their lives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Slow down</title><link>https://awolski.com/slow-down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/slow-down/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some days you wake up with a heavy feeling hanging over you. Ahead of you lies another day of grind. The mountain of things to do seems to only get bigger, the peak further away. On days like this you tend to view your role as &lt;strong>&lt;em>getting through&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> the day rather than &lt;strong>&lt;em>being in it&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is how I felt earlier this week. I lay in bed with that heavy, despondent feeling, another day of churn ahead of me, knowing I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be satisfied regardless of how much I achieved.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But instead of &lt;em>sucking it up and getting on with it&lt;/em> I decided to come downstairs slowly, make a cup of coffee, and just sit on the couch quietly. After some time I took out my journal and did my morning reflection &lt;em>slowly&lt;/em>, taking care with each letter, each word I wrote. I contemplated what each task meant instead of the usual quick glance. I savoured each sip of coffee. Then I started working on my first task, not trying to &lt;em>just get through it&lt;/em>, but to do a good, thoughtful job. Strangely I started to feel better. Happy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Let go</title><link>https://awolski.com/let-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/let-go/</guid><description>&lt;p>Everything you own feels like it is necessary. The services you subscribe to seem essential. Everything on your to-do list seems important. But when you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re forever chasing your tail and there&amp;rsquo;s never enough time in the day, eventually something has to go. It&amp;rsquo;s difficult to decide what to cull, but after the initial withdrawal you wonder how you ever found time in the first place. It turns out very little is essential, it&amp;rsquo;s just hard to let things go.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Guidelines for less distracting email</title><link>https://awolski.com/guidelines-for-less-distracting-email/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/guidelines-for-less-distracting-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently started checking email only once per week. Last week I spent a mere twenty-eight minutes in my inbox. The difference between this new routine and the old, distracted, daily one is massive, and has made a significant impact on my ability to get big, important things done. However Derek Sivers&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="https://sivers.org/pe">recent post&lt;/a> on using a private email address for close friends made me question whether checking email so infrequently would have the detrimental effect of removing a source of connection with my family and friends. I wondered whether I should consider a similar approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After some though my answer is a resounding no; my way is just fine. Firstly, I hate duplication, and fanatically try to reduce the number of accounts I manage. In my opinion there are better ways to filter the signal from the noise than by opening a separate email account. Second, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to check email often or be distracted by notifications. Friends and family can reach me by phone when necessary, emergency or otherwise. A delay of a few days for more thoughtful correspondence shouldn&amp;rsquo;t matter for everything else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With that said, there are a couple of guidelines you can follow to extract as much value from email as possible while removing its ability to &lt;em>take valuable time and attention from you&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monthly reflection - September 2019</title><link>https://awolski.com/monthly-reflection-september-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/monthly-reflection-september-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each month I look back over the month&amp;rsquo;s entries in my Bullet Journal to extract the things I&amp;rsquo;ve achieved, things that are going well or not so well, patterns that are emerging, and any lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned. The process takes a long time, usually in the order of 3-4 hours, but I find the value I derive from it is well worth the effort. This month I want to experiment a little by publishing some of my notes, firstly to reinforce the lessons I learn, but also because, who knows, maybe someone else will find it valuable too.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Don't put up a zero</title><link>https://awolski.com/dont-put-up-a-zero/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/dont-put-up-a-zero/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the start of September I set myself a target of publishing two blog posts per week, on Tuesday and Friday. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter what they were, I just had to ship something. The intention, I kept reminding myself, is to build the habit of writing, and not to worry about the quality of what I&amp;rsquo;m putting out. If I kept at it, by the end of September I&amp;rsquo;d have eight posts under my belt. By the end of the year, thirty-six. In ten years time, if I maintain the same schedule, I will have published over a thousand posts, and by then I will have improved and, in the process, learned a thing or two about writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been anything but easy. Tuesdays and Fridays have been tough slogs, consisting of long hours spent writing and rewriting, and then rewriting some more. I find it an arduous task to put into words what I&amp;rsquo;m finding interesting and learning, all the while trying to block out the fear of &lt;em>what people will think&lt;/em>. I have to keep telling myself I&amp;rsquo;m writing for me, not for anyone else.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then life goes and gets in the way. You&amp;rsquo;ve got this thing that you&amp;rsquo;re committed to but along comes a day when the weight of the world is on your shoulders, the universe urging you to lay down and give up. A headache. A sickness. An argument with your partner. Whatever. The last thing you want to do is &lt;strong>&lt;em>get to work&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>. This is how I feel today. It&amp;rsquo;s Friday and I have to ship, but the last thing I feel like doing is sitting down to write.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Year without alcohol</title><link>https://awolski.com/year-without-alcohol/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/year-without-alcohol/</guid><description>&lt;p>A good friend of mine, &lt;a href="http://control-alt-delete.net">Damian Fisher&lt;/a>, recently decided to give up alcohol for a year. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited for him, I get a little buzz when people decide to make big positive changes in their lives. I have little doubt removing booze from his life will result in huge benefits. Why so sure? Because I recently took a year off booze myself, and in doing so transformed my relationship with alcohol, improving my life immeasurably. It has been nine months since I finished my year, and with Damo just starting his, I thought it an opportune time to write about my experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reflection</title><link>https://awolski.com/reflection/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/reflection/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every morning and every evening, at the end of each week, and at the end of the month, I sit down with my &lt;a href="bujo">Bullet Journal&lt;/a> and go through my reflection routine. I look at the day, week or month and ask myself questions — and write down my answers to — like: &lt;em>What went well? What didn&amp;rsquo;t go so well? What did I learn? What patterns are emerging? What did I achieve? How can I improve?&lt;/em> The process helps me keep on top of the busyness of life, remain focussed on what&amp;rsquo;s important, review my progress and acknowledge my achievements. It&amp;rsquo;s also creating a wonderful resource for me to look back on, both now and later in life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something that I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed after reviewing my reflection entries is how habitual a creature I am. I repeat the same behaviour — the same mistakes — over and over again. Even after acknowledging a mistake or a habit one month, and defining an approach to rectify it in the next month, I&amp;rsquo;ll repeat the mistake and journal about it, completely oblivious of the original entry months prior.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s an example&amp;hellip; In my January &lt;strong>Lessons Learned&lt;/strong> I wrote &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;Being honest is better than bottling things up&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> — probably in the context of how I handled a disagreement or annoyance with my wife. This last week (September) in my weekly reflection I wrote: &lt;em>&amp;quot;&lt;strong>Learned&lt;/strong>: Spoke calmly, open and honestly to Em about [an issue]. Has been good since then.&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Nearly nine months between the two instances and I&amp;rsquo;m still reverting to default behaviour when I&amp;rsquo;m frustrated, which is to remain quiet, bottle it up and give her the cold shoulder for a day or two.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generalisation, specialisation and financial independence</title><link>https://awolski.com/generalisation-specialisation-financial-independence/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/generalisation-specialisation-financial-independence/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading about financial independence a lot lately. I like to think of myself as &lt;em>temporarily&lt;/em> financially independent — I&amp;rsquo;m 3.5 months into a sabbatical and have enough money saved to not have to worry about working for at least another year. One of the better books I&amp;rsquo;ve read on the subject of FI is &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Early-Retirement-Extreme-Philosophical-Independence/dp/145360121X/">&lt;em>Early Retirement Extreme&lt;/em>&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s a gold mine of strategies, tactics and principles to help you achieve FI, and personally, forced me to re-think my place in the world and how I want to spend my time in it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An important ideal brought up in ERE is that of the Renaissance man; one who strives to develop his abilities to their full extent in many areas of life. A Renaissance man, Fisker explains, obtains knowledge in a wide range of subjects and excels at many different things. He is a polymath, a jack-of-all-trades. &lt;strong>&lt;em>&amp;ldquo;The Renaissance man is capable of many different things and doesn&amp;rsquo;t restrict himself to vocational skills. He does his own taxes and researches his own investments. He can fix a computer or a broken appliance. He knows how to drive and fix a car, but he has enough time and athletic ability to ride his bicycle 20 miles instead, or run five miles to get groceries. He can play an instrument, dance, paint, or write creatively. He can recreate interesting meals from scratch rather than recipe.&amp;quot;&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> One of the many advantages of becoming a Renaissance man, Fisker explains, is that you become less reliant on outsourcing your life and operations, which keeps you in paid employment (a Salary man).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, to achieve financial independence it is desirable to be a &lt;strong>generalist&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Habit tracking</title><link>https://awolski.com/habit-tracking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/habit-tracking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Habit tracking has become a huge win for me this year. The knowledge I&amp;rsquo;ve gained reading Atomic Habits combined with my Bullet Journal habit tracker have helped me cultivate good habits and eliminate bad habits that I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled with for years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I keep it simple and commit to a maximum of five habits each month, but rarely more than four. I find I lose focus and get overwhelmed if I try to do too much. I use the columns in my Bullet Journal&amp;rsquo;s monthly collection, one column for each habit I&amp;rsquo;m tracking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2019-09-13-habit-tracking.png" alt="Habit Tracking">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A guide to spending less time on your phone</title><link>https://awolski.com/a-guide-to-spending-less-time-on-your-phone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/a-guide-to-spending-less-time-on-your-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently read Ryan Holiday&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href="https://forge.medium.com/a-radical-guide-to-spending-less-time-on-your-phone-a5419b1538ee">A Radical Guide to Spending Less Time on Your Phone&lt;/a>. The post is full of great advice to help reduce your phone use and well worth a read. Holiday is spot on — our phones have become an instant escape, and a constant burden. We find it easier to whip them out in moments of idleness than be alone with our thoughts. We feel compelled to find out what the latest ping was irrespective of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing in the moment. This behaviour becomes compulsive. We reach for our phones without thinking, reinforcing those neural pathways that keep us from being fully present with our friends, family, children&amp;hellip; our lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What struck me most about the post was how evolved my own phone reduction habits have become. I have already implemented most of what Holiday suggests, and in some instances pushed the boundaries even further.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this in mind I thought I would follow up with my own strategies to reduce the time I spend on my phone. Some of these overlap with Ryan Holiday&amp;rsquo;s strategies, some have spawned from Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s blog and book &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Digital-Minimalism-Living-Better-Technology/dp/0241341132/">Digital Minimalism&lt;/a>, while others I&amp;rsquo;ve devised on my own by simply becoming more aware of my behaviour. I have much healthier, productive relationship with my phone as a result.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Gaining wisdom and saving £50,000</title><link>https://awolski.com/gaining-wisdom-and-saving-50k/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/gaining-wisdom-and-saving-50k/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post started out with the title &lt;em>How a Book Saved Me £50,000&lt;/em>. Part way through writing it, however, I realised it was a specific example of a more general, more valuable concept: how we can improve ourselves and our lives by applying the knowledge — the wisdom — that others have worked hard to acquire.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Employ your time in improving yourself by other men&amp;rsquo;s writings, so that you should gain easily what others have laboured hard for. — Socrates&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I wish I&amp;rsquo;d read &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/Early-Retirement-Extreme-Philosophical-Independence/dp/145360121X/">Early Retirement Extreme&lt;/a> (ERE) 9 years ago when I first added it to my reading list. Had I done so I might well be financially independent already. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I read it when I did, though, because in doing so I avoided ploughing myself into another £50,000 of debt, and years of work required to pay it off. It was a close call though. I had my finger on the button. I was hours away from picking up the phone, firstly to try and negotiate the quote we&amp;rsquo;d been given, but ultimately to give the go ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As fate would have it I had also started reading ERE in the days prior. On page 4 I underlined a sentence, &lt;em>&amp;quot;&amp;hellip;with tens of thousands being spent on marginal increases in functionality.&amp;quot;&lt;/em> The note was marked with an asterix, and at the bottom of the page I wrote some &lt;a href="https://ryanholiday.net/marginalia-the-anti-library-and-other-ways-to-master-the-lost-art-of-reading/">marginalia&lt;/a>: &lt;strong>Currently pondering a £50,000 extension and garage conversion&lt;/strong>. In the days and pages that followed my outlook was completely transformed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2019-09-06-ere-marginalia.jpg" alt="ERE marginalia">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Regret</title><link>https://awolski.com/regret/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/regret/</guid><description>&lt;p>In my early thirties I watched a &lt;a href="https://www.ted.com/talks/stefan_sagmeister_the_power_of_time_off">TED talk&lt;/a> about the power of time off in which the speaker, Stefan Sagmeister, presents an infographic showing a typical, modern-day working life: 25 years for learning, 40 years for working, and 15 years for retirement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2019-09-03-typical-working-life.png" alt="Typical working life">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He then cuts 5 years from the retirement section and intersperses them throughout the working section.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2019-09-03-working-life-rethought.png" alt="Working life rethought">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The audience laughs and applauds; it seems they think the idea is as novel as I do. Such a simple idea, but for me, profound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The idea stayed with me, and in the years that followed I dreamed of taking my first sabbatical. I was never sure it would be possible financially, or whether I would have the guts follow through, so for a long time it remained only a dream. But I continued to speak about the TED Talk with friends and family and in doing so fanned the flames of the dream. I worked hard, caught a few lucky breaks, and in my late thirties, when the possibility of a sabbatical somehow seemed more realistic, I tentatively began telling people about my &amp;lsquo;plans&amp;rsquo;. One friend commented &amp;ldquo;If it were anyone else I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe them, but I reckon you will.&amp;rdquo; I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Implementing Atomic Habits</title><link>https://awolski.com/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Jerry Seinfeld&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Don&amp;rsquo;t Break the Chain&lt;/em> method to try and exercise every day. Each day I exercise I put an X in my Bullet Journal monthly spread. If I miss a day I get a big blank spot and a broken chain. The idea is that motivation comes from not wanting to break the streak of Xs you&amp;rsquo;ve built up. Seinfeld used the method to ensure he was writing jokes every day. My experiment is working well; I&amp;rsquo;ve exercised on 53 of a possible 59 days to date. However there is always room for improvement, 6 out of 59 days worth of improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The motivation I get from wanting to keep my streak alive is significant. On a number of occasions I&amp;rsquo;ve been ready to get into bed before remembering I hadn&amp;rsquo;t exercised that day, so I&amp;rsquo;ve busted out a few sets of max push-ups beside the bed in my pyjamas, just to keep the streak alive. But I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that I can&amp;rsquo;t always rely on &lt;em>Don&amp;rsquo;t break the chain&lt;/em> motivation, or my memory, to get me over the line. Enter &lt;strong>&lt;em>habit stacking&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>&lt;em>temptation bundling&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>, two techniques I learned recently from a book called Atomic Habits (see my book notes &lt;a href="books/atomic-habits">here&lt;/a>).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bullet Journal Method</title><link>https://awolski.com/bujo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/bujo/</guid><description>&lt;p>Starting a Bullet Journal in 2019 has been the single most impactful thing I&amp;rsquo;ve done this year. It has transformed the way I organise my life and forced me to spend more time offline. It has integrated journaling, from which I already derive greate value, with the power of a simple organisational system. I feel more in control, less overwhelmed, and clearer than I ever have. It is still early days, but I get the feeling my Bullet Journal is here to stay.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nice 70.3</title><link>https://awolski.com/nice-70_3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/nice-70_3/</guid><description>&lt;p>On 16th September 2018 I finished my first &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ironman_70.3">Ironman 70.3&lt;/a>. It was a fantastic event and experience, one in which I felt all the highs and lows I anticipated in the lead up: nerves, excitement, frustration, desperation, relief.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A friend and I signed up for the 70.3 on the 6th February this year. We had been looking for a challenge to occupy our time and minds whilst undertaking a &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/show">year without alcohol&lt;/a>. I had previously trained for a 70.3 back in 2010 before kids were on the radar. When marriage and kids came along training fizzled out, but a seed had been planted and I always felt I would revisit it in the years to come. When my friend suggested Nice 70.3 all the other options we were considering went out the window. For me, the half Ironman was it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What will you have to show for it?</title><link>https://awolski.com/show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/show/</guid><description>&lt;p>This question was put to me by a friend on a recent night out (pint of cider in his hand) about the purpose of my dry year, which I&amp;rsquo;m nearly half way through. My initial, unconvincing response was that, at the very least, I&amp;rsquo;ll have completed a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ironman_70.3">70.3&lt;/a>, to which he again queried &amp;ldquo;You couldn&amp;rsquo;t have done that anyway?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His playful jibe, and my meek response, got me thinking more deeply about my decision. What do I really want out of this year? Could it be obtained with alcohol along for the ride?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turning 39</title><link>https://awolski.com/39/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/39/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tomorrow I turn 39. It feels like a significant birthday, like a milestone. As if tomorrow is my 40th, not my 39th. Maybe my mind is sending a strong message that I&amp;rsquo;ve only got one year left until the milestone really is here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I watched with interest as a number of my friends crossed the 40 mark over the last few years. Some of them did so without flinching. Others&amp;hellip; well, from the outside it looked as if they had a harder time. Mostly, for the ones who seemed to struggle the most, it appeared as though turning 40 was a bit of a wake-up call; a reminder that the clock is ticking and they&amp;rsquo;d better get a wriggle on with a few things. I started thinking about my own life as a result; how I would like to feel as I neared 40, and what would need to be done in the run-up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An imminent birthday is an ideal time to reflect on the year just gone, to savour what you have right now, and cast your eye out into the future. This post is intended for these purposes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Reducing email</title><link>https://awolski.com/reducing-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/reducing-email/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>This is your life and it&amp;rsquo;s ending a minute at a time - Fight Club&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This quote from Fight Club is an idea I take seriously. It may sound morbid, but it helps me to cull the trivial and shallow from my life, creating more time to focus on what I truly value. Lately, email has been an annoying time thief.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am increasingly frustrated with the number of emails I have to process. The newsletters I never read, the feature updates for services I don&amp;rsquo;t use, new terms of service, feedback requests, payment confirmations etc. These messages are informational, unactionable, unnecessary. I don&amp;rsquo;t need or want to see them. So I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented some strategies to stem the flow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your choices shape your identity</title><link>https://awolski.com/your-choices-shape-your-identity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/your-choices-shape-your-identity/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Every time you choose to do the easy thing, instead of the right thing, you are shaping your identity, becoming the type of person who does what’s easy, rather than what’s right. — Hal Elrond, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B013PKZUOW">The Miracle Morning&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I highlight a lot of passages and take a lot of notes as I read. Some passages I highlight are forgotten shortly after consumption. Others remain firmly lodged in my mind, and go on to influence my thoughts and actions for weeks, months and years. Occasionally something I read threatens to shape the person I am and who I become for the rest of my life. The above is one of the latter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How often do you let a single bad day ruin the rest of your week? You eat something shit, you miss a workout, or you fail to do something you promised yourself you would do. But instead of rectifying the failing today, you vow that you&amp;rsquo;ll get back on track next week. &amp;ldquo;Next week will be a good week. Next week I&amp;rsquo;ll smash it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Bullshit.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Improve your eyesight with focused training</title><link>https://awolski.com/improve-your-eyesight-with-focused-training/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/improve-your-eyesight-with-focused-training/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel lucky to live in an era in which we&amp;rsquo;re no longer constrained by widely accepted beliefs, like the belief that once we reach a certain age our brain is fixed and we&amp;rsquo;re no longer able to learn in any significant way. Take this excerpt from Anders Ericsson&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B019CH3M10">Peak&lt;/a> for example:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The general belief was that once a person reached adulthood, the wiring of his or her brain was pretty much fixed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>We now know:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip; the brain&amp;rsquo;s structure and function are not fixed. They change in response to use. It is possible to shape the brain — your brain, my brain, anybody&amp;rsquo;s brain — in ways that we desire through conscious, deliberate training.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Personally I find it incredibly encouraging to know that our brains possess this plasticity and we can be optimistic for the future, knowing that whatever we set our mind to we can achieve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An example of our brain&amp;rsquo;s plasticity presented in the book struck me as something that I&amp;rsquo;d experienced before&amp;hellip; improving my ability to read smaller text on my laptop&amp;rsquo;s screen.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Clear the obstacles for tomorrow's success</title><link>https://awolski.com/clear-the-obstacles-for-tomorrows-success/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/clear-the-obstacles-for-tomorrows-success/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I sit down to write this, the path has been cleared for me to simply wake up and get started on &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pareto_principle">the vital few&lt;/a>; namely, the activities I&amp;rsquo;ve identified as contributors to my success and happiness. The mundane tasks and chores that need to be done on a day-to-day basis are complete, and no longer stand the way — as obstacles or excuses — of me finishing the activities that are vital to my growth and success, e.g. meditating, reading, writing, exercising.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This &lt;em>&lt;strong>clearing-the-obstacles&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> routine has contributed hugely to the success I&amp;rsquo;ve had in my personal development endeavours over the past few months. Clearing the decks by doing all of the &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered, I&amp;rsquo;ll do it tomorrow&amp;rdquo; chores like washing up, clearing the kitchen, putting out your workout clothes etc. pays &lt;strong>massive dividends&lt;/strong> when it comes to getting the important things — the vital few — done each day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2016 mini review</title><link>https://awolski.com/2016-mini-review/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/2016-mini-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>2016 is history, and before I get too far into 2017 I thought I should take some time to reflect on the year just passed, and the things I value most that occurred within it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Appearing clueless in extraneous matters</title><link>https://awolski.com/appearing-clueless-in-extraneous-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/appearing-clueless-in-extraneous-matters/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“If you wish to improve,” Epictetus once said, “be content to appear clueless or stupid in extraneous matters.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ahhhh&amp;hellip; that feels good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I came across this wise piece of advice whilst reading &lt;a href="http://observer.com/2016/11/want-to-really-make-america-great-again-stop-reading-the-news/">Want to Really Make America Great Again? Stop Reading the News&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://ryanholiday.net/">Ryan Holiday&lt;/a>. It feels good because I&amp;rsquo;m more often than not uninformed — unaware even — about extraneous matters like current events. Holiday goes on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>One of the most powerful things we can do as a human being in our hyperconnected, 24/7 media world is say: “I don’t know.” Or, more provocatively: “I don’t care.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Even better. It&amp;rsquo;s incredibly comforting to know that smart men have adopted the same beliefs and behaviours you have. Particularly when you occasionally question those beliefs and behaviours because they don&amp;rsquo;t conform with those of the general population.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One month without coffee</title><link>https://awolski.com/one-month-without-coffee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/one-month-without-coffee/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sipping on my first cup of coffee in over a month. I have to admit it does taste pretty good. However I only made this cup to experience it one more time, to experience what I had for so many years. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I&amp;rsquo;m going back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started my month without coffee experiment for a number of reasons:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Local GitHub Pages in one command (with Docker)</title><link>https://awolski.com/local-github-pages-in-one-command-with-docker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/local-github-pages-in-one-command-with-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>I wiped and installed &lt;a href="http://www.apple.com/uk/macos/sierra/">macOs Sierra&lt;/a> on Macbook Pro on the weekend, something I like to do regularly to hone my reboot procedure with &lt;a href="https://github.com/awolski/dotfiles">my dotfiles&lt;/a> repo. Part of that procedure is to get my blog up and running, which runs on Jekyll and GitHub Pages. I like to edit a blog post locally, and run &lt;code>bundle exec jekyll serve&lt;/code> to see how the layout looks locally before I push to GitHub.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first installed Jekyll I installed &lt;a href="https://rvm.io/">rvm&lt;/a> to manage and install Ruby. However I don&amp;rsquo;t write Ruby code and find it&amp;rsquo;s overkill to have to install it simply to start my blog. After all, I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;strong>minimalist&lt;/strong>, and I only really want to work in a terminal and a browser.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting from trapped to untrapped</title><link>https://awolski.com/getting-from-trapped-to-untrapped/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/getting-from-trapped-to-untrapped/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was putting the finishing touches on the blog post I wrote yesterday about &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/enjoying-a-lifetime-with-a-bit-of-work">enjoying a lifetime with a bit of work&lt;/a> and found myself on Jay Austin&amp;rsquo;s blog reading his recent posts. Aside from the initial pang of jealousy I had about the amount of travel he enjoys, I was struck by a couple of quotes and how closely they aligned the direction I&amp;rsquo;m taking my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In his post &lt;a href="http://www.jayaustin.info/2016/08/recap-reboot.html">Recap, Reboot&lt;/a> he muses:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>the little house wasn&amp;rsquo;t an ends, but a means: a means to live a clutter-free life and a debt-free life—and later, a carbon-free life—a house that wouldn&amp;rsquo;t tie me down with financial and physical and mental burdens&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And later:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;about getting from trapped to untrapped, inhibited to uninhibited, about the big changes I&amp;rsquo;ve made-but-haven&amp;rsquo;t-actually-yet-written-about that have helped me live a more intentional life&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Getting from &lt;strong>trapped to untrapped&lt;/strong>&amp;hellip; big changes that have helped me live a &lt;strong>more intentional life&lt;/strong>. To &lt;strong>live a clutter-free life&lt;/strong> and a &lt;strong>debt-free&lt;/strong> life. These are the outcomes and ideals that occupy my mind, and I&amp;rsquo;ve begun &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/enjoying-a-lifetime-with-a-bit-of-work">writing about&lt;/a> and working towards.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enjoying a lifetime with a bit of work</title><link>https://awolski.com/enjoying-a-lifetime-with-a-bit-of-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/enjoying-a-lifetime-with-a-bit-of-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I watched the &lt;a href="http://minimalismfilm.com/">minimalism film&lt;/a> for the second time last night, and I enjoyed it even more this time around. It certainly won&amp;rsquo;t be the last time I watch it. There is a minimalist&amp;rsquo;s travel bag chock-full of incredible quotes and realisations, and inspiring people and real life examples in the film.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I really am gravitating more and more to a more minimalist lifestyle, and I can feel the momentum building towards some major lifestyle changes. Some of my friends and family would say that I&amp;rsquo;m already a minimalist, but I disagree. My answer&amp;hellip; How can I be so minimalist when I have still have so much &lt;strong>unnecessary&lt;/strong> debt hanging over my head?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m drawn to the whole concept of minimalism, tiny houses, efficient spaces, owning and consuming less. To having more time with which I choose to do what I want. A lot of this isn&amp;rsquo;t possible right now, because of the lifestyle that myself and my family have, the things we own, and the decisions we&amp;rsquo;ve made. Some of it isn&amp;rsquo;t even desirable. I guess what I&amp;rsquo;m really drawn to is the idea of a more deliberate life, rather than going through the motions. Bucking the status quo so to speak&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docker Compose slow on Docker for Mac and public wifi</title><link>https://awolski.com/docker-compose-slow-with-docker-for-mac-and-public-wifi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/docker-compose-slow-with-docker-for-mac-and-public-wifi/</guid><description>&lt;p>On a recent visit to a Caffé Nero coffee shop, &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/compose/reference/overview/">docker-compose&lt;/a> commands were running &lt;strong>extremely&lt;/strong> slowly. After an hour or so of restarting Docker, my Mac, and switching back an forth between &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/installation/mac/#/docker-for-mac">Docker for Mac&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/machine/">Docker Machine&lt;/a>, I just gave up and headed home, pinning the issue on the then-still-beta Docker for Mac.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I encountered the same problem, in a different Caffé Nero and on a stable version of Docker for Mac. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be just a coincidence. A quick search brought me to &lt;a href="https://github.com/docker/compose/issues/3419">this&lt;/a> GitHub issue, and in particular this answer:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Hi guys&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>127.0.0.1 localunixsocket&lt;/code> to &lt;code>etc/hosts&lt;/code> solved the issue for me&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And sure enough, updating &lt;code>/etc/hosts&lt;/code> to include &lt;code>127.0.0.1 localunixsocket&lt;/code> fixed the issue immediately.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Failing aws cli on Docker container with old date time</title><link>https://awolski.com/failing-aws-cli-on-docker-container-with-old-date-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/failing-aws-cli-on-docker-container-with-old-date-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I hit an issue which completely stumped me (for a while). Running an &lt;code>aws s3 cp&lt;/code> from a Docker container — that had &lt;em>never&lt;/em> failed before in the same scenario — was failing every time with &amp;lsquo;&lt;code>A client error (403) occurred when calling the HeadObject operation: Forbidden&lt;/code>&amp;rsquo;. When run from my Mac directly with the same &lt;code>AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID&lt;/code> and &lt;code>AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY&lt;/code> it worked. &lt;strong>WTF!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OnePlus 2 fingerprint sensor not working? Turn off gestures</title><link>https://awolski.com/oneplus-2-fingerprint-sensor-not-working-turn-off-gestures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/oneplus-2-fingerprint-sensor-not-working-turn-off-gestures/</guid><description>&lt;p>My OnePlus 2 fingerprint sensor stopped working about a month ago. I thought it must have been a delayed result of my 1 year old boy hurling it into the bath and it being submerged on the bottom for a good 5 seconds. But my wife was quick to react and rushed it to intensive care (a bowl full of rice), and after a couple of days — and to my surprise — the phone worked perfectly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the next week or so was convinced it would start to fail. And I was right; probably about 3 weeks post bath incident the fingerprint sensor died. I was disappointed, but with the backup of on-screen buttons it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the end of the world; it was still usable.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Problem installing jq on OS X using Homebrew</title><link>https://awolski.com/problem-installing-jq-on-os-x-using-homebrew/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/problem-installing-jq-on-os-x-using-homebrew/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is just a quick post for reference as I had issues installing &lt;a href="https://stedolan.github.io/jq/">jq&lt;/a> on my machine this evening.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The things you discover... httpie and jq</title><link>https://awolski.com/the-things-you-discover-jq-and-httpie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/the-things-you-discover-jq-and-httpie/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes working with technology you feel so far behind the eight ball. Like, how do you &lt;strong>not&lt;/strong> know about some of the awesome tools out there that &lt;em>could&lt;/em> have made your life so much easier before now. This week I was introduced to two such tools, &lt;a href="https://github.com/jkbrzt/httpie">httpie&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://stedolan.github.io/jq/">jq&lt;/a>. I just know that the combination of these two command line apps are going to come in real handy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My 2015 year of writing in review</title><link>https://awolski.com/my-2015-year-of-writing-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/my-2015-year-of-writing-in-review/</guid><description>&lt;p>Note: I started this post on new year&amp;rsquo;s eve and am only just getting around to finishing it now. Not a good start to my writing year!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>2015 is winding down. Em has taken the kids out to a park with a friend and her kids, leaving me with a couple of hours to myself. So I thought I&amp;rsquo;d reflect on the year was, in writing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Writing — particularly in the technical arena — was a key focus for me at the start of the year, based on a journal entry I wrote in January. Here&amp;rsquo;s a snippet from that entry:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Writing has the effect of forcing you to understand a topic, and it conveys that understanding to the rest of the (tech) world (or at least the ones that stumble across your blog).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My goal in 2015 is to completely leapfrog everyone at my company, become the no-questions-asked go-to guy at &lt;em>insert_company&lt;/em>, and develop a presence within the worldwide Java community&amp;hellip; even if it&amp;rsquo;s just a very small presence.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Remote debugging with Node.js on Vagrant</title><link>https://awolski.com/remote-debugging-with-node-js-on-vagrant/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/remote-debugging-with-node-js-on-vagrant/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently worked out worked out how to remote debug from my Macbook Pro to a Node.js server running on a CentOS 6.6 VirtualBox VM created by Vagrant. No more development tools like WebStorm on a VM as I can now use them from my Mac.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The problem with email</title><link>https://awolski.com/the-problem-with-email/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/the-problem-with-email/</guid><description>&lt;p>It seems to me that email is not the most effective means of communication anymore. I could count dozens of instances in recent yearsin which there have been serious disconnects in the teams and organisations I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for, in which information is not getting to all the relevant parties. Like the synapses of our collective brain were not connected all the required neurons.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I read a great article, &lt;a href="http://ben.balter.com/2015/11/12/why-urls/">Why everything should have a URL&lt;/a> which made some great points about the deficiencies of email and today&amp;rsquo;s default workflow. The quote below is taken from the section &lt;a href="http://ben.balter.com/2015/11/12/why-urls/#todays-default-workflow">Today&amp;rsquo;s default workflow&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Most organizations today transact business almost entirely through email and in-person meetings. Absent an additional step whereby participants go out of their way to capture and share context, organization knowledge primarily lives in two places: in employees’ heads, and in their inbox. If that employee leaves the organization, or if they win the lottery and don’t show up on Monday (read: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bus_factor">bus factor&lt;/a>), a significant amount of information — information essential to the organization’s continued operation — leaves with them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Think through some common scenarios where a team member might need to gain additional context they weren’t originally privy to: they could have been out of the office when a decision was made (humans do silly things like getting sick or making other, smaller humans), they could have been on a different team at the time, heck, maybe they weren’t even part of the organization at the time. Whatever the reason, they became a stakeholder mid-decision or post-decision, and thus lack the context necessary to properly participate going forward, especially not on equal footing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How is that essential context shared? In many organizations I suspect the answer is “I guess you had to be there. I think Bob was there that day, you should go ask him”. Assuming you can find Bob’s desk, he’s in the office that day, free at the moment, and remembers a meeting that potentially happened months or years earlier, you might be able to get your question answered, but that process doesn’t scale as people constantly move around and new team members are onboarded. Bob could hunt through his inbox and forward a stream of emails for you to read through in reverse chronological order, but that’s likely neither efficient nor very helpful for either party involved (“can you forward me the attachment?”).&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Ain&amp;rsquo;t that the truth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Book Review - Minimalism: Live a Meaningful Life</title><link>https://awolski.com/book-review-minimalism-live-a-meaningful-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/book-review-minimalism-live-a-meaningful-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I picked up this &lt;a href="http://www.theminimalists.com/lml/">book&lt;/a> the day after Christmas when both my wife and I were overwhelmed with the sheer quantity of gifts that we and this kids had been given for Christmas. I spent the early part of that day reading the free PDF version of the book, and then finishing the majority of it in the bath with a glass of wine in the evening. The rest of the day, in between playing with the kids with their new toys, was dedicated to a huge toy cull and reorganisation minimalisation. We just didn&amp;rsquo;t have the space for anything to put the new things, and we were both completely overwhelmed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So onto the book…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Upgrade Docker on Travis CI</title><link>https://awolski.com/upgrade-docker-on-travis-ci/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/upgrade-docker-on-travis-ci/</guid><description>&lt;p>If you need to make use of Docker&amp;rsquo;s latest and greatest features — like &lt;a href="http://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/builder/#arg">build time arguments&lt;/a> — in your travis-ci builds, you can easily do so by upgrading the default docker-engine version travis-ci&amp;rsquo;s build environment. Read on to find out how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fixing node-gyp make failed on centos in Docker</title><link>https://awolski.com/fixing-node-gyp-make-failed-on-centos-in-docker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/fixing-node-gyp-make-failed-on-centos-in-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had this issue pop up time and time again, so I wanted to document it so that I won&amp;rsquo;t forget in the future. The error below occurs when executing &lt;code>RUN npm install sinopia&lt;/code> in a Dockerfile FROM centos:6.6 (no doubt this isn&amp;rsquo;t specific to Docker).&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">node-gyp configure build
&amp;lt;span style&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;color:red;&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;gyp WARN EACCES user &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;undefined&amp;#34;&lt;/span> does not have permission to access the dev dir &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/root/.node-gyp/0.12.7&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
gyp WARN EACCES attempting to reinstall using temporary dev dir &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/sinopia/node_modules/fs-ext/.node-gyp&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
make: Entering directory &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">`&lt;/span>/usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/sinopia/node_modules/fs-ext/build&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74"> CXX(target) Release/obj.target/fs-ext/fs-ext.o
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;lt;span style=&amp;#39;&lt;/span>color:red;&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;&amp;gt;make: g++: Command not found
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">make: *** [Release/obj.target/fs-ext/fs-ext.o] Error 127&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">make: Leaving directory `/usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/sinopia/node_modules/fs-ext/build&amp;#39;&lt;/span>
&amp;lt;span style&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;color:red;&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;gyp ERR! build error
gyp ERR! stack Error: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">`&lt;/span>make&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">`&lt;/span> failed with exit code: &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2&lt;/span>
gyp ERR! stack at ChildProcess.onExit &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>/usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/npm/node_modules/node-gyp/lib/build.js:269:23&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span>
gyp ERR! stack at ChildProcess.emit &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>events.js:110:17&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span>
gyp ERR! stack at Process.ChildProcess._handle.onexit &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>child_process.js:1074:12&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span>
gyp ERR! System Linux 4.1.12-boot2docker
gyp ERR! command &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;node&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;/usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/npm/node_modules/node-gyp/bin/node-gyp.js&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;configure&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;build&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
gyp ERR! cwd /usr/local/node/lib/node_modules/sinopia/node_modules/fs-ext
gyp ERR! node -v v0.12.7
gyp ERR! node-gyp -v v2.0.1
gyp ERR! not ok
npm WARN optional dep failed, continuing crypt3@0.1.8&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>The error seems obvious at first glance; g++ is not installed. But adding that as one of the packages I install at the top of the Dockerfile had no effect whatsoever.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Starting and using a service during Docker build</title><link>https://awolski.com/starting-services-during-docker-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/starting-services-during-docker-build/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Problem&lt;/strong>: You&amp;rsquo;re building a image from a Dockerfile and you need to interact with a running process during the build of the said image. How? I really struggled with this question for some time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve since discovered the solution. Read on to find out how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My specific use case is this: start a local npm registry — &lt;a href="https://github.com/rlidwka/sinopia">sinopia&lt;/a> — that acts as a proxy with an uplink to another npm registry. Run &lt;code>npm install --registry http://localhost:4873/&lt;/code> for a bunch of node modules, which pulls the node modules into the storage directory of the sinopia proxy. Then package up the the proxy sinopia instance as a distributable registry with all dependencies in its &lt;code>storage&lt;/code> directory.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I first got started with Docker I tried this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-dockerfile" data-lang="dockerfile">&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">RUN&lt;/span> sinopia --config /opt/sinopia/config.yaml&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">RUN&lt;/span> npm install --registry http://localhost:4873/ &amp;lt;package&amp;gt;&lt;span style="color:#960050;background-color:#1e0010">
&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>But I soon realised this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. In this example, by the time the second RUN command executes, sinopia is no longer running. That layer of &lt;a href="https://docs.docker.com/engine/introduction/understanding-docker/#how-does-a-docker-image-work">Union File System&lt;/a> has already been committed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Making Time Blocking Work with Google Calendar</title><link>https://awolski.com/making-time-blocking-work-with-google-calendar/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/making-time-blocking-work-with-google-calendar/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s Study Hack&amp;rsquo;s blog, and have made several attempts at adopting a number of his practices, like &lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/2009/06/08/drastically-reduce-stress-with-a-work-shutdown-ritual/">daily shutdown rituals&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/2014/08/08/deep-habits-plan-your-week-in-advance/">weekly planning&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/2013/12/21/deep-habits-the-importance-of-planning-every-minute-of-your-work-day/">time blocking&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve had varying degrees of success implementing these rituals. However none of them — over the long term — have become a habit that has stuck.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This post is will focus on a fresh attempt at integrating time blocking into my daily work routine, with a few tweaks that I hope will overcome the problems I&amp;rsquo;ve had in the past. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to explain what time blocking is&amp;hellip; head on over to Cal Newport&amp;rsquo;s original post &lt;a href="http://calnewport.com/blog/2013/12/21/deep-habits-the-importance-of-planning-every-minute-of-your-work-day/">Deep Habits: The Importance of Planning Every Minute of Your Work Day&lt;/a>, and
&lt;a href="http://www.makeuseof.com/tag/time-blocking-secret-weapon-better-focus/">Time Blocking — The Secret Weapon to Better Focus&lt;/a> for those details.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Random 'Permission denied (publickey)' error in Travis</title><link>https://awolski.com/sudden-permission-denied-publickey-error-in-travis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/sudden-permission-denied-publickey-error-in-travis/</guid><description>&lt;p>This morning I hit a random issue in Travis (Pro), in that all of a sudden a build could not clone a GitHub repository:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">Installing an SSH key from: default repository key
Key fingerprint: 5e:fd:38:1f:01:e2:f0:87:8e:77:91:e7:70:37:c0:14
3.68s
$ git clone --depth&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">50&lt;/span> --branch&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>my-branch git@github.com:my-organisation/my-repo.git my-organisation/my-repo
Cloning into &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;my-organisation/my-repo&amp;#39;&lt;/span>...
Warning: Permanently added the RSA host key &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> IP address &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;192.30.254.137&amp;#39;&lt;/span> to the list of known hosts.
Permission denied &lt;span style="color:#f92672">(&lt;/span>publickey&lt;span style="color:#f92672">)&lt;/span>.
fatal: Could not read from remote repository.
Please make sure you have the correct access rights and the repository exists.
The command &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;eval git clone --depth=50 --branch=my-branch git@github.com:my-organisation/my-repo.git my-organisation/my-repo&amp;#34;&lt;/span> failed. Retrying, &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">2&lt;/span> of 3.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Problems building a CentOS AWS AMI with Packer</title><link>https://awolski.com/building-an-aws-ami-with-packer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/building-an-aws-ami-with-packer/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in the early stages of working with (awesome) tools like Packer and &lt;a href="https://www.terraform.io/">Terraform&lt;/a> and I ran into a few issues whilst trying to create a base image that mirrors the production environment we&amp;rsquo;re deploying to. I wanted to document them here to a) engrain what I&amp;rsquo;m learning and b) document the solutions for future reference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Refactoring with Groovy and runtime method invocation</title><link>https://awolski.com/refactoring-with-groovy-and-runtime-method-invocation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/refactoring-with-groovy-and-runtime-method-invocation/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can do some pretty awesome things with Groovy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the language in a number of projects for a couple of years now, and won&amp;rsquo;t even think about whether to include it in anything new. It&amp;rsquo;s in. No question. (Unless the enterprise forbids it.. rolling). I love the dynamic aspect of it. I love closures. I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> love how easy the language makes it when working with Maps and Json (which I do a lot of lately); dot notation for field/attribute access is sooo powerful.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-groovy" data-lang="groovy">&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">def&lt;/span> map &lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#f92672">[&lt;/span>firstName: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;Marty&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">,&lt;/span> surname: &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;McFly&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">]&lt;/span>
println map&lt;span style="color:#f92672">.&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">firstName&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Last week I managed to take that power a little bit further by using dynamic/runtime method invocation. Reflection in Java but made &lt;em>groovy&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Scratching the surface of GPG</title><link>https://awolski.com/scratching-the-surface-of-gpg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/scratching-the-surface-of-gpg/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is just a reference really to document my beginnings with GPG so that I can refer to it in the future. The &lt;a href="https://www.gnupg.org/gph/en/manual.html">GNU Privacy Handbook&lt;/a> is a great reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On OS X GPG isn&amp;rsquo;t installed by default so install it:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">MacOSX&amp;gt; brew install gpg
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Signing in to EC2 instance with an AWS generated key pair</title><link>https://awolski.com/signing-in-to-ec2-instance-with-an-aws-generated-key-pair/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/signing-in-to-ec2-instance-with-an-aws-generated-key-pair/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I hit an issue signing in to an new ec2 instance using a private key I generated and downloaded on AWS.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">ssh -i ~/.aws/mykey.pem &amp;lt;ip_address&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>I was getting this error:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@
@ WARNING: UNPROTECTED PRIVATE KEY FILE! @
@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@
Permissions &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">0640&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">for&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#39;/Users/awolski/.aws/mykey.pem&amp;#39;&lt;/span> are too open.
It is required that your private key files are NOT accessible by others.
This private key will be ignored.
bad permissions: ignore key: /Users/awolski/.aws/my-key.pem
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Great freelance advice from Roberto Cortez at Devoxx UK 2015</title><link>https://awolski.com/great-freelance-advice-from-roberto-cortez-at-devoxx-uk-2015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/great-freelance-advice-from-roberto-cortez-at-devoxx-uk-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-08-12-roberto-cortez.png" alt="What if I fail">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading through my Feedly feed this morning I found &lt;a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/throwback-monday-devoxx-uk-and-devoxx-poland-were-awesome/">this post&lt;/a> by &lt;a href="http://">Oleg Shelajev&lt;/a> which contained a link to all of the &lt;a href="https://www.parleys.com/channel/5593acf0e4b028e237b4b0c8">Devoxx UK 2015 talks&lt;/a> hosted on Parleys. Awesome sauce.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.devoxx.co.uk/">Devoxx UK conference&lt;/a> was a couple of months ago so I&amp;rsquo;d forgotten all about it (no, sadly I didn&amp;rsquo;t go), but it was great to be made aware of the valuable resources. I get two very contrasting feelings when browsing libraries of conference talks like this. The first is over excitement at all the great content and new things that I&amp;rsquo;m going to learn by watching them all. This is always and immediately followed by the thought:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>How the f*%$ am I going to find time to consume all of this?!&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>AWS access control policies and IAM best practices</title><link>https://awolski.com/aws-access-control-policies-and-iam-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/aws-access-control-policies-and-iam-best-practices/</guid><description>&lt;p>I watched a couple of great videos today on AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) best practices, and what&amp;rsquo;s possible with access control policies. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post a few of the key takeaways here in order to drum them home, and for future reference.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The videos I watched were &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?t=33&amp;amp;v=Rkr5enrsMks">Mastering Access Control Policies (SEC302) | AWS re:Invent 2013&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Rkr5enrsMks" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Enabling ssh access to VMWare virtual machine</title><link>https://awolski.com/enabling-ssh-access-to-vmware-virtual-machine/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/enabling-ssh-access-to-vmware-virtual-machine/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of creating a Vagrant box for a VMWare VM for a machine I&amp;rsquo;m working on, the end goal being fully automated development environment built so that new developers can get up and running quick-smart.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Java Stormpath SDK behind a Proxy using Shiro JndiObjectFactory</title><link>https://awolski.com/stormpath-java-sdk-behind-a-proxy-using-shiro-jndiobjectfactory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/stormpath-java-sdk-behind-a-proxy-using-shiro-jndiobjectfactory/</guid><description>&lt;p>I needed to develop an application that used the Java Stormpath SDK from behind a corporate proxy. The SDK has a &lt;a href="https://docs.stormpath.com/java/apidocs/index.html?com/stormpath/sdk/client/Proxy.html">Proxy&lt;/a> class just for this purpose, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to the &lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/documentation/spec-136004.html">JavaBeans specification&lt;/a> (a good explanation of which can be found &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/3295517/2309046">here&lt;/a>). The Proxy class has two constructors, both with arguments, and its fields are final. Because I&amp;rsquo;m using Apache Shiro and initialising the Stormpath client using a &lt;a href="https://shiro.apache.org/configuration.html">shiro.ini configuration file&lt;/a>, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see a way to set the Proxy on the ClientBuilder where it was needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure whether this design is intentional or not. Maybe the Proxy class was created without much thought about Shiro integration. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m missing something. But I can&amp;rsquo;t find any documentation about how to configure it without doing so in code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still needed a solution though&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I discovered Shiro&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://shiro.apache.org/static/1.2.3/apidocs/org/apache/shiro/jndi/JndiObjectFactory.html">JndiObjectFactory&lt;/a>, which allows you to look up objects in JNDI from your shiro.ini. Using the approach I&amp;rsquo;ll explain below, I was able to use my system&amp;rsquo;s already configured Java proxy settings - if they are configured - but not have to change any code if I continue develop the application in a non-proxy environment, like at home.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using Docker to spin up databases for development</title><link>https://awolski.com/using-docker-to-spin-up-databases-for-development/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/using-docker-to-spin-up-databases-for-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>Using Docker to spin up production-like databases during application development can help take out the uncertainty of whether your changes will work when deployed to production. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how I use Docker to create a clean MySQL database that mirrors production each time a start development on a new feature.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever been developing something for a long period of time, making changes to your development database as you go, and then when you&amp;rsquo;ve gone to integrate it into staging or production things haven&amp;rsquo;t quite worked? You&amp;rsquo;ve had to manually write scripts to &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; things, or try and get back to your clean development database state by exporting, copying and importing&amp;hellip; all manually via your database client?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If this sounds like you (as it did me), you&amp;rsquo;ll be pleased to know there are better ways to manage your development database workflow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Considering Microservices</title><link>https://awolski.com/considering-microservices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/considering-microservices/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the most valuable blogs I subscribe to is &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/">Martin Fowler&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a>. I say valuable because every post he creates makes me a better developer. His posts are always thoughtful, insightful, detailed and thorough. You just know each one packs so much experience behind it you&amp;rsquo;d have to be a fool not to take his insights board.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Having myself been swept up in the hype of microservices — what he and the ThoughtWorks Technology Radar group call &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/techniques/microservice-envy">microservices envy&lt;/a> — I was interested to read his latest post &lt;a href="http://martinfowler.com/bliki/MicroservicePremium.html">MicroservicePremium&lt;/a>, in which he explains under what circumstances, or complexity, a microservice architecture becomes preferable over a monolithic one.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Connecting to MySQL on Vagrant guest on Windows</title><link>https://awolski.com/connecting-to-mysql-on-vagrant-guest-on-windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/connecting-to-mysql-on-vagrant-guest-on-windows/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I set up a Vagrant box with Tomcat, MariaDB and a couple of Java web applications so that our testers could quickly get started on their own private instances. Being able to run locally, upgrade the applications and database when they like will be a real productivity win for us&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not saying anything about the efficiency of IT support ;-).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a GitHub repository for the Vagrant-Tomcat-MariaDB setup, which you can view &lt;a href="https://github.com/awolski/vagrant-tomcat7-mariadb">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One problem I had a bit of trouble with connecting to the MariaDB database on the VM using our regular MySQL client. We run on Windows here, so SSH is not available without installing another tool like PuTTy or similar. Typically when we create a connection it&amp;rsquo;s using localhost, but becuase the VM is effectively another machine with its own IP address, and you&amp;rsquo;re trying to connect over SSH, things get a bit tricky. It is possible though, and here&amp;rsquo;s how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blogging with Google voice to text</title><link>https://awolski.com/blogging-with-google-voice-to-text/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/blogging-with-google-voice-to-text/</guid><description>&lt;p>Things have been so busy recently that I have been finding it difficult to create time to write. There just seems to be so much going on in life: family life, kids, work, trying to get a side business off the ground, maintaining some level of fitness by doing a WOD 4 to 5 times a week, let alone all the day to day things that need to get done. Even getting up at 5am, there&amp;rsquo;s only ever an hour or so at the end of the day before I go to bed at 10pm, during which I&amp;rsquo;m usually getting some coding or reading done.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I got to thinking, how can I &amp;ldquo;hack&amp;rdquo; my way to achieve my goal of blog posting 5 times per week when time is so limited? Squeeze in an hour at work? Write before I go to bed? I was coming up short with viable options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then last Friday my new Oneplus One arrived. I played around with it for most of Friday night, and then off and on over the weekend. One thing that I discovered worked amazingly well that I&amp;rsquo;d never really used before is Google&amp;rsquo;s speech to text functionality. I was gob-smacked at how easy it was to use, and how accurate it was. I soon began to wonder whether it could be the answer to my non-blogging dilemma.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I &amp;lsquo;typed&amp;rsquo; out this post using it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mockito Javadoc. The best use of Javadoc, ever</title><link>https://awolski.com/mockito-javadocs-the-best-use-of-javadoc-ever/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/mockito-javadocs-the-best-use-of-javadoc-ever/</guid><description>&lt;p>Whilst writing a few test cases this morning using &lt;a href="https://github.com/mockito/mockito">Mockito&lt;/a> as my mocking framework, I was browsing Mockito&amp;rsquo;s official &lt;a href="http://site.mockito.org/mockito/docs/current/org/mockito/Mockito.html">documentation&lt;/a>. I was particularly impressed with the conciseness of the examples and explanations. In no time at all I had the information I needed. Then it dawned on me that these beautifully formatted, thoroughly useful help pages were generated using the &lt;a href="https://www.google.co.uk/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0CCkQFjAB&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.oracle.com%2Ftechnetwork%2Farticles%2Fjava%2Findex-jsp-135444.html&amp;amp;ei=YJoZVfD-BYTcas7XgOgN&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFEz_fxLI435eayi9HEMEKceAL3vw&amp;amp;sig2=1UR3I3TiBO_Uj3xfQMZVUg">Javadoc documentation tool&lt;/a>&amp;hellip; I was gobsmacked. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen such a fantastic use of Javadoc before. In fact, I was a bit jealous that I&amp;rsquo;d never thought to use the Javadoc tool in such away before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-03-30-mockito-docs.png" alt="Mockito Javadocs">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I keep up with the rapid pace of tech</title><link>https://awolski.com/how-i-keep-up-with-the-rapid-pace-of-tech/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/how-i-keep-up-with-the-rapid-pace-of-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently attended the London edition of &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar">Thoughtworks&amp;rsquo; Tech Radar&lt;/a> event. I really enjoyed the gathering, as it introduced me to a range of &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/techniques">Techniques&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/tools">Tools&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/platforms">Platforms&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/languages-and-frameworks">Languages &amp;amp; Frameworks&lt;/a>. And it was great to the hear the opinions of two really in-touch, smart and interesting guys, including &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pub/ian-cartwright/0/952/282">Ian Cartwright&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-03-29-feedly-1.jpg" alt="Feedly">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the questions that was put to the speakers was:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;lsquo;How do you keep up to date with all of these technologies, languages and frameworks?&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It was a good question, and one to which I could sense the rest of the room interested in hearing the answer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The benefits of waking early - part 2</title><link>https://awolski.com/the-benefits-of-waking-early-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/the-benefits-of-waking-early-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last week I wrote about &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/the-benefits-of-waking-early/">the benefits of waking early&lt;/a> in the wake of my recent switch to pre-5:30am starts each day (pardon the pun).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The day after I published my post, my old Crossfit box owner Pete Rankine echoed similar (and more elaborate) sentiments on &lt;a href="http://www.theboatshedfitness.co.uk/">The Boat Shed&lt;/a>&amp;lsquo;s WOD &lt;a href="http://www.theboatshedfitness.co.uk/2015/03/19/friday-20-03-2015/">blog&lt;/a>. Hearing Pete&amp;rsquo;s thoughts really reinforced my own goals, and my drive to continue the habit of waking early.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The whole post is definitely worth a read, but I particularly liked:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;The number one excuse for not working out is the lack of time. After having a long day at work, going to the gym can easily become a small priority. Waking up before 6 am allows you to hit the gym before starting your workday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The benefits of waking early</title><link>https://awolski.com/the-benefits-of-waking-early/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/the-benefits-of-waking-early/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve found it difficult in the past to maintain, for any decent stretch of time, the practice of waking up early. There have been periods during which I have woken early for a few weeks, possibly even a few months, but it&amp;rsquo;s never &amp;lsquo;stuck&amp;rsquo; like I would like it to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But recently I&amp;rsquo;ve made it happen. It was the jet lag after our 7 week in Australia that began the trend, starting with the 4am wake up my daughter gave me the day after we got back. But since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting up at or before 5:30am consistently. And I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s going to change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How? I think the main reason is that now that I&amp;rsquo;ve got young children, I place an extremely high premium on any spare time that I get to myself. To exercise, to think, and to get things done. And the only time there is available to do those things - not when you&amp;rsquo;re exhausted after a full day of work and kids - is early in the morning.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting featured on stormpath.com</title><link>https://awolski.com/getting-featured-on-stormpath-com/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/getting-featured-on-stormpath-com/</guid><description>&lt;p>At the start of 2015 I set myself a goal to contribute more to the worldwide Java community. Getting involved in community discussions, forums and social media. Responding to more questions on &lt;a href="http://stackoverflow.com/">Stackoverflow.com&lt;/a>. Contributing to an open source project (I&amp;rsquo;m still yet to choose which one(s)). I also started open sourcing some of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing in my spare time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a result of open sourcing one particular &lt;a href="https://github.com/awolski/client-api">project&lt;/a> on &lt;a href="https://github.com/">GitHub&lt;/a>, I was contacted by &lt;a href="https://stormpath.com/">Stormpath&lt;/a>, asking if they could feature my project on their website.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code faster</title><link>https://awolski.com/code-faster/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/code-faster/</guid><description>&lt;p>Some of the shortcuts that modern IDEs offer can significantly increase the efficiency at which developers churn out code. The problem is, a lot of developers don’t bother learning them. However if you invest a bit of time each day learning the keyboard shortcuts, code assist and coding templates of your IDE and you’ll have your feet up while your colleagues are still hard at it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Turn up</title><link>https://awolski.com/turn-up/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/turn-up/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a rollercoaster of self improvement for years and years now. I remember the first time I actually paid for a program; 300 odd quid for Anthony Robbin&amp;rsquo;s Personal Power II back when I was about 27. Since then I&amp;rsquo;ve been on a long journey and have tried (and failed at) many, many self improvement initiatives. It&amp;rsquo;s a journey that I am by no means remotely close to finishing&amp;hellip; The self improvement (or Kaizen) journey is one that never really ends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However even though I&amp;rsquo;ve got more on my plate than I ever have before (including two young children under the age of three) I feel more, let&amp;rsquo;s call it balanced, than I ever have in my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve got an amazing family around me. I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good physically because I&amp;rsquo;m consistently doing WODs. I&amp;rsquo;m feeling great about my career because I&amp;rsquo;ve worked myself into a position where I have autonomy and a certain level of influence. Life is good, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t even feel like too much of an effort like it has done in the past.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Chances are someone's coded it already. Better.</title><link>https://awolski.com/chances-are-someones-coded-it-already.-better./</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/chances-are-someones-coded-it-already.-better./</guid><description>&lt;p>Before you go and write that feature or half-baked code or API, spend some time searching for it. Search in your own code base, on Google, on GitHub, anywhere. Because chances are, somebody has already written code that does exactly what you need. Better than the half-baked shite you&amp;rsquo;re about to churn out too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-01-09-code-reuse.gif" alt="Code Reuse">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Immutable. Um, no it isn't</title><link>https://awolski.com/immutable-um-no-it-isnt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/immutable-um-no-it-isnt/</guid><description>&lt;p>When you&amp;rsquo;re working on a large project for which the code base has been around for a long time, you have the pleasure (cough) of seeing some pretty &amp;lsquo;interesting&amp;rsquo; code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today for example, I had to use an existing model object. I noticed in the class level comment the word &amp;lsquo;Immutable.&amp;rsquo; Having recently read about Google&amp;rsquo;s AutoValue Java library for immutable value objects, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d look to see just how &amp;lsquo;immutable&amp;rsquo; this object really is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple and powerful Java metrics with... Metrics</title><link>https://awolski.com/simple-and-poejava-metrics-with-metrics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/simple-and-poejava-metrics-with-metrics/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;re aware that part of your application is performing poorly and you need to find out exactly what and where, fast. So what do you do? You whack in a few &lt;code>System.currentTimeMillis();&lt;/code> calls, subtract the difference and do some conversions, right? WRONG. Give yourself a clip over the ears. And then go and check out &lt;a href="https://dropwizard.github.io/metrics">Metrics&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-01-06-metrics.png" alt="Metrics Java Library">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Never lose a code snippet again with GistBox</title><link>https://awolski.com/never-lose-a-code-snippet-again-with-gistbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/never-lose-a-code-snippet-again-with-gistbox/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I discovered a tool that is going to save me countless hours looking for old code snippets, scripts and commands. Today I discovered &lt;a href="http://www.gistboxapp.com/">GistBox&lt;/a>. If you&amp;rsquo;re not already familiar with the application, or with &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/">GitHub Gists&lt;/a>, read on and save yourself a bit of time and frustration.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2015-01-05-GistBox.png" alt="Gistbox">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Enable hot-deployment with Tomcat + Eclipse + Ivy</title><link>https://awolski.com/enable-hot-deployment-with-tomcat-eclipse-ivy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/enable-hot-deployment-with-tomcat-eclipse-ivy/</guid><description>&lt;p>I occasionally forget how to configure Tomcat and Eclipse so that my code changes hot-swapped into the JVM when running a web application in debug. Here&amp;rsquo;s how&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Integrating JOOQ... easy</title><link>https://awolski.com/integrating-jooq-easy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/integrating-jooq-easy/</guid><description>&lt;p>Integrating &lt;a href="http://www.jooq.org/">JOOQ&lt;/a> into your application is a &lt;a href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=piece%20of%20piss">piece of piss&lt;/a>, as I discovered recently when I needed to build some non-ORM/Hibernate database access into some reports. I&amp;rsquo;m upgrading the reports component of an application I develop and needed to add some &lt;em>performant&lt;/em> metrics. I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to use direct SQL or JDBC, so I decided to see how JOOQ performed&amp;hellip; and I was pleasantly surprised at how simple it was to set up and use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Mini journal with Twitter, IFTTT and Evernote</title><link>https://awolski.com/mini-journal-with-twitter-ifttt-and-evernote/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/mini-journal-with-twitter-ifttt-and-evernote/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve often wished I had kept a diary throughout the years. Friends and family will recollect things that have completely vanished from my memory, and I&amp;rsquo;ll think to myself &amp;ldquo;If only I had jotted something down about that I could go back to and trigger some of those memories.&amp;rdquo; But alas, I never manage to maintain a regular journal schedule; only in fits and starts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-11-04-ifttt-twitter-evernote-1.png" alt="IFTTT-Twitter-Evernote">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Cloudbees continuous delivery summit part II</title><link>https://awolski.com/cloudbees-continuous-delivery-summit-part-ii/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/cloudbees-continuous-delivery-summit-part-ii/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I went to the &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/cloudbees-cd-summit/">Accelerating Innovation with Continuous Delivery summit&lt;/a> at &lt;a href="http://www.thebrewery.co.uk/">The Brewery&lt;/a> in London, a free one day event hosted by &lt;a href="http://www.cloudbees.com/">CloudBees&lt;/a>. It was a really well organised event with some great speakers, and I’ve got Moleskin full of notes and ideas to take back to the office and try and somehow integrate into our development/delivery processes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the highlights for me was &lt;a href="http://blog.xebialabs.com/author/aphillips/">Andrew Phillips&lt;/a>’ — VP of Products at XebiaLabs — talk on the Three Pillars of Continuous Delivery: Culture, Tooling &amp;amp; Practices. He made a valid point that it’s a reality that “10 kids with some financing and a bit of software can put you out of business.” And It’s so true. Big enterprises that are slow to adopt these new trends, tools and practices which enable fast, robust software delivery — providing real value to customers when they need it — are at real risk of being left behind. This was a theme was echoed by other speakers throughout the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At one point he asked the audience “who here [who’s company] practices Agile?” Pretty much every hand in the room went up. He then stuck up a slide which read:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>“Our highest priority is to satisfy the customer through early and continuous delivery of valuable software.”&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>and asked “Who practices this?” Not a lot of hand went up. But those who really know their agile would be aware that this is the &lt;a href="http://agilemanifesto.org/principles.html">#1 Principle of the Agile Manifesto&lt;/a>. I was shocked. My company says that it’s Agile. Not according to the Agile manifesto we’re not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Template SoapUI tests with XmlSlurper</title><link>https://awolski.com/template-soapui-tests-with-xmlslurper/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/template-soapui-tests-with-xmlslurper/</guid><description>&lt;p>In between urgent bug fixes and planned sprint work I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find time to write an automated test suite with &lt;a href="http://www.soapui.org/">SoapUI&lt;/a> to verify some of the things we can&amp;rsquo;t in &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/unit-tests-worth-their-weight-in-gold/">unit tests&lt;/a>. After writing a few SoapUI tests by copying the same SOAP request between test cases, but slightly modifying the content of one or two elements, I wondered whether it would be &lt;del>easier&lt;/del> smarter to reuse a template SOAP request and somehow replace only the element/attribute content that differs between tests.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With a little bit of Groovy (specifically &lt;a href="http://groovy.codehaus.org/Reading+XML+using+Groovy's+XmlSlurper">XmlSlurper&lt;/a>) you can, and here&amp;rsquo;s how I did it.*&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Unit tests: worth their weight in gold</title><link>https://awolski.com/unit-tests-worth-their-weight-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/unit-tests-worth-their-weight-in-gold/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the whole of today, and a large chunk of yesterday, I laboured away writing a single unit test. Without context 1.5 days for a single unit test sounds pretty bad, but in my defence, the test involved mocking out numerous services and a deep understanding of the underlying model and a complex part of the system in order to set up the scenario I was trying to test. Because of this complexity, and the possibility of inadvertantly breaking existing functionality and/or business rules, I wanted to make &lt;em>damn sure&lt;/em> my changes were sound.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-09-02-unit-testing.gif" alt="Test confidence">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dev manager, read this</title><link>https://awolski.com/dev-manager-read-this/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/dev-manager-read-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>I clipped a link to &lt;a href="http://www.activestate.com/blog/2014/08/microservices-and-paas-part-i">this article&lt;/a> earlier this week, thinking it was one of the best things I&amp;rsquo;ve read on micro-services and continuous, PaaS and continuous delivery all year. But to be sure, I wanted to revisit it later, hence the clip to Evernote. I&amp;rsquo;ve just re-read it now, and it is. So many great nuggets of &lt;del>information&lt;/del> experience to draw on from people who have been there, done that. It&amp;rsquo;s the sort of article you just want to stick on your development manager&amp;rsquo;s desk and with a note saying &amp;ldquo;this is how we need to be developing, deploying, delivering.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laptop upgrade part 2</title><link>https://awolski.com/laptop-upgrade-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/laptop-upgrade-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m loving the &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/laptop-upgrade/">new Macbook&lt;/a> Pro Retina (3.0GHz Dual-core Intel Core i7, 16GB 1600MHz DDR3L SDRAM). It&amp;rsquo;s a beautiful machine, and so far it has been a joy to use. My first order of business was to setup an environment from which I can work from home, which means VMWare hosting Windows. I&amp;rsquo;ve dedicated 4GB RAM to it and it runs like a dream, and with three finger swipe and can switch between it and my other OS X workspaces in no time. And it&amp;rsquo;s nice to see even with Windows running in a virtual machine, I&amp;rsquo;ve still got 10GB+ of RAM left to play with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before I wipe my old laptop - an early 2008 black Macbook with 2.4Ghz Core 2 Duo, 4GB RAM, 128GB SSD - I thought I&amp;rsquo;d run some benchmarks on the old machine and the new one to see how much more productive (cough) I&amp;rsquo;m going to be.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Request your GitHub username</title><link>https://awolski.com/request-your-github-username/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/request-your-github-username/</guid><description>&lt;p>Consistency is a good thing. It&amp;rsquo;s nice (though increasingly rare) to have the same username on all the sites you use on the web. But unless you&amp;rsquo;ve got some random mashing of letters and numbers, it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to &amp;lsquo;nab&amp;rsquo; your preferred username.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I joined GitHub, this was the case for me. &lt;a href="https://github.com/awolski">awolski&lt;/a> was gone, so I had to opt for &lt;em>akwolski&lt;/em> instead. Now you might say &amp;ldquo;big deal, it&amp;rsquo;s only on letter.&amp;rdquo; But it irked me nonetheless. I own &lt;a href="https://awolski.com/">awolski.com&lt;/a>. My Twitter handle is &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/awolski">awolski&lt;/a> (although I rarely tweet). I use &lt;a href="https://bitbucket.org/awolski">awolski&lt;/a> on Bitbucket.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I &lt;em>wanted&lt;/em> awolski on GitHub!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Parallel deployment in Tomcat</title><link>https://awolski.com/parallel-deployment-in-tomcat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/parallel-deployment-in-tomcat/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for the &lt;del>right&lt;/del> best way to deploy an application with zero downtime. My search led me to a nifty feature introduced into Tomcat 7 called &lt;a href="http://tomcat.apache.org/tomcat-7.0-doc/config/context.html#Parallel_deployment">parallel deployment&lt;/a>. Parallel deployment allows you to deploy multiple versions of a web application with the same context path at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;ve got an awesome application running on Tomcat at the url &lt;code>http://yourdomain.com/awesomeapp&lt;/code>. Normally You deploy the war — something like &lt;code>awesomeapp-1.0.0.war&lt;/code> — to &lt;code>$CATALINA_HOME/webapps/&lt;/code>. You&amp;rsquo;ve modified the &lt;code>path&lt;/code> element of your context.xml file so that your app is reachable at the aforementioned url. You realise you need to deploy a new version of your app because &lt;em>&amp;lt;insert your reason here&amp;gt;&lt;/em>, but you don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to bring down the whole application server and deploy the new version of the app.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With Tomcat 7 you don&amp;rsquo;t have to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Laptop upgrade</title><link>https://awolski.com/laptop-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/laptop-upgrade/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today I pulled the trigger on the purchase of a new laptop. Shit. I feel a little bit guilty sometimes for spending so big, because I&amp;rsquo;m pretty &lt;del>tight&lt;/del> conservative when it comes to buying stuff (just ask my wife and friends). But as with all purchases this big, I find myself constantly questioning, and then trying to validate the spend&amp;hellip; like I&amp;rsquo;ve got a devil on one shoulder saying &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;go on, you know you want to&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em> and an angel on the other &lt;em>&amp;ldquo;you&amp;rsquo;re current laptop is just fine, you don&amp;rsquo;t need a new one.&amp;quot;&lt;/em> Today, finally, the devil won out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll love it when it arrives, and the spend will be justified.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Attracting the best developers</title><link>https://awolski.com/attracting-the-best-developers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/attracting-the-best-developers/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was whittling away at my Feedly feed tonight (which has built up in recent weeks, no small thanks to my colicky new baby boy Bodhi) when I reached an article from the Typesafe blog, &lt;a href="http://typesafe.com/blog/qa-with-kevin-webber">Q&amp;amp;A with Kevin Webber&lt;/a>. One sentence in particular caught my attention:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The caliber of candidates we interviewed at Nurun shot up significantly after introducing Scala to the organization which goes to show that Scala can be a real boost to hiring top-tier developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the second time in as many days I&amp;rsquo;ve read or watched something with these sentiments — that the tools and technologies you choose, as a business, has a significant impact on the type of developer you&amp;rsquo;re likely to attract.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CloudBees CD summit</title><link>https://awolski.com/cloudbees-cd-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/cloudbees-cd-summit/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve just registered for the &lt;a href="http://www.cloudbees.com/cdsummit">CloudBees continuous delivery summit&lt;/a> in London on 9th September.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-08-11-CD-Summit.png" alt="CD Summit">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been drawn to continuous integration/delivery ever since I joined a company that had adopted &lt;em>zero&lt;/em> continuous integration practices; I&amp;rsquo;m talking a fully manual process from commit, to build, to copy an artefact to a production environment. I implemented a number of improvements there, and brought that experience to my current company, but I still feel like I&amp;rsquo;m only just scratching the surface. So I was pumped at the prospect of a free seminar with what looks to be a pretty good lineup:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build scripts - don't modify my files!</title><link>https://awolski.com/build-scripts-dont-modify-my-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/build-scripts-dont-modify-my-files/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my pet hates when it comes to development is a build script or an IDE that modifies project/config files so that the project looks like it&amp;rsquo;s modified in the IDE.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-08-06-modified-scm-project.png" alt="Modified">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I check out a project from source control, whether it be Subversion, Git, Mercurial&amp;hellip; whatever, until I physically open and edit a (not ignored) file in that project, I only want to see that little yellow cylinder looking thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-08-06-unchanged-scm.png" alt="Unchanged">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Modern Java developer</title><link>https://awolski.com/modern-java-developer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/modern-java-developer/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was reading through my Feedly feed a couple of days ago and came across &lt;a href="http://jaxenter.com/the-in-tools-ten-technologies-you-should-know-about-50852.html">this article&lt;/a>, a repost of Zero Turnaround&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://zeroturnaround.com/rebellabs/10-kick-ass-technologies-modern-developers-love/">10 Kick Ass Technologies Modern Developers Love&lt;/a>. I was pleasantly surprised as I read through the list that I know and frequently use the majority of them:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Confluence&lt;/strong> - We use Confluence for &lt;del>all&lt;/del> most of the technical documentation at my company; in fact, I wrote an internal blog post a few days ago. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice, intuitive application, and really easy to use. It still feels like it&amp;rsquo;s got a lot of work to go into it - that it&amp;rsquo;s not as polished as JIRA - but the it&amp;rsquo;s by far the best online document management tool I&amp;rsquo;ve used.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Git&lt;/strong> - As a developer, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard about or used Git by now&amp;hellip; where the hell have you been? I use Git for my personal projects, and have been pushing to get it at the my company for quite a while now (we still use SVN - Linus Torvalds gives his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4XpnKHJAok8">opinion about SVN here&lt;/a>). I&amp;rsquo;m by no means a Git expert, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning more and more all the time. And I can without hesitation vouch for Git&amp;rsquo;s power.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Specifying the location of shiro.ini</title><link>https://awolski.com/specifying-the-location-of-shiro-ini/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/specifying-the-location-of-shiro-ini/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on switching the identity and security management libraries in one of my applications from &lt;a href="http://docs.jboss.org/seam/3/security/latest/reference/en-US/html/security-identitymanagement.html">Seam Security/PicketLink IDM&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="http://shiro.apache.org/">Shiro&lt;/a> backed by &lt;a href="https://stormpath.com/">Stormpath&lt;/a>. Shiro and Stormpath are really quite easy to set up, and there are some &lt;a href="https://github.com/stormpath/stormpath-shiro/wiki">good guides&lt;/a> out there to help you get up and running. For me, everything was going really well in my local development environment, but when I finally pushed these changes to my hosting provider, &lt;a href="http://jelastic.com/">Jelastic&lt;/a>, I hit an issue&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Liquibase against an existing database, part 2</title><link>https://awolski.com/running-liquibase-against-an-existing-database-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/running-liquibase-against-an-existing-database-part-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>It turns out integrating liquibase into an existing project/database is a lot easier than I originally thought&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially, I thought &lt;a href="http://www.liquibase.org/documentation/ant/changelogsync_ant_task.html">changelogsync&lt;/a> need to be executed against your database first, in order for the Liquibase tables to be created and have your database marked as in a &amp;lsquo;from now on we&amp;rsquo;re on Liquibase&amp;rsquo; state. And when I looked back over the &lt;a href="http://www.liquibase.org/documentation/existing_project.html">existing project documentation&lt;/a>, I thought they had messed up the section &amp;lsquo;We are going to use Liquibase starting&amp;hellip; NOW!':&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Instead of building up a changeLog to match your existing database, you can instead just declare “from now on we are using Liquibase”. The advantage to this is that it much easier to set up because it is just a mandate. Usually this works best going from one version to the next because your databases are all in a reasonably consistent state and you simply start tracking database changes in your next version using Liquibase. Because Liquibase only looks at the DatabaseChangeLog table to determine what needs to run, it doesn’t care what else might be in your database and so it will leave all your existing tables alone and just run the new changeSets.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Deep Work</title><link>https://awolski.com/deep-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/deep-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through some pretty complicated technical design at work; some of the hardest development stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve done. Ever. The changes I&amp;rsquo;ll be making to the are in some complex parts of the system. My understanding of how the code works must be high; my confidence of not breaking it with my changes, even higher. Over the last couple of weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve had my head down working through the code, the problems I have to solve, and how best to merge two elegantly together. It&amp;rsquo;s been a hard slog, made up of long periods of time spent with my headphones in, debugging, backtracking, cursing&amp;hellip; struggling through a little documented domain… trying to get it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today I nailed it. All the pieces just seemed to fall into place. I saw exactly how all the moving bits would fit together, perfectly, and elegantly. I really understood.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Accessing Stormpath Client when using shiro.ini</title><link>https://awolski.com/access-stormpath-client-when-using-shiro-ini/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/access-stormpath-client-when-using-shiro-ini/</guid><description>&lt;p>I ran into a problem recently while trying to get access to the &lt;code>com.stormpath.sdk.client.Client&lt;/code> instance when it is initialised by &lt;a href="http://shiro.apache.org/documentation.html">Apache Shiro&lt;/a>&amp;lsquo;s &lt;code>shiro.ini&lt;/code> configuration. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any help in the &lt;a href="http://shiro.apache.org/webapp-tutorial.html">Shiro&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://github.com/stormpath/stormpath-shiro/wiki">Stormpath&lt;/a> documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Initially I was creating a separate instance of &lt;code>com.stormpath.sdk.client.Client&lt;/code> in code, but I realised I was having to duplicate configuration by specifying &lt;code>apiKeyFileLocation&lt;/code> and &lt;code>cacheManager&lt;/code> config in both shiro.ini and in environment variables/context parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the end it was a simple task of looking into the Shiro and Stormpath source code to find out what is exactly happening&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>First Impressions of Ghost</title><link>https://awolski.com/first-impression-of-ghost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/first-impression-of-ghost/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve stuck with Blogger as my blogging platform for the last few years, mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s free, but also because it&amp;rsquo;s tied to my Google account and integrates well with other Google services like Google+ and Adsense. But mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There a a couple of gripes I have with Blogger:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It is just plain painful if you want to dig into the HTML and CSS to make any changes to the layout. Yes it is possible, but after several attempts over the years, with varying degrees of success, I just don&amp;rsquo;t understand why they&amp;rsquo;ve made it so difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The editor is hideous. I can never get my posts to display the way that I want. More often than not I have to switch to the HTML editor and painstakingly pull out the plethora of &lt;code>&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;/code> and other elements placed &lt;em>everywhere&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I first read about the &lt;a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost Blogging Platform&lt;/a> while reading Jeff Atwood&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/10-years-of-coding-horror/">10 Years of Coding Horror&lt;/a>. If someone with as much blogging clout as Jeff Atwood has made the switch, that&amp;rsquo;s endorsement enough for me. So I moseyed on over to the Ghost site to check it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my first impressions are really, really positive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MD5 Checksums</title><link>https://awolski.com/md5-checksums/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/md5-checksums/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tonight I downloaded and installed &lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/downloads/jdk8-downloads-2133151.html">JDK8&lt;/a> on my Macbook. I&amp;rsquo;m keen to get started playing around with the some of new features, in particular Lambdas and the &lt;a href="http://download.java.net/jdk8/docs/api/java/util/stream/Stream.html">Streams API&lt;/a>; I really think these will streamline some of my code without having to incorporate Groovy (or similar) to get similar features, and then having to mess about with different compilers and Maven/Gradle plugins.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I digress&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tonight, for the first time ever, I verified the MD5 checksum of a file I downloaded. Now I know that&amp;rsquo;s not breaking news, but it struck me as&amp;hellip; weird? shocking?&amp;hellip; that in the 15+ years I&amp;rsquo;ve been pulling stuff off the world wide web, I&amp;rsquo;ve never before tonight thought (or been bothered) to check that what I&amp;rsquo;m downloading is what I think it is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dead wood</title><link>https://awolski.com/dead-wood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/dead-wood/</guid><description>&lt;p>Dead wood:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>People in a group or organization who are not useful any more and who need to be removed.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; &lt;a href="http://idioms.thefreedictionary.com/dead+wood">The Free Dictionary&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know the type. That guy that arrives 15 minutes late, and leaves 15 minutes early. The first application he opens each morning is his browser. And how does he spend the first hour on the job? Hint: it&amp;rsquo;s not the functional specification he&amp;rsquo;s meant to be writing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Is it time to get off the JSF bandwagon?</title><link>https://awolski.com/is-it-time-to-get-off-the-jsf-bandwagon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/is-it-time-to-get-off-the-jsf-bandwagon/</guid><description>&lt;p>I watched a pertinent video tonight: &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ygW8fJVlDxQ">&amp;ldquo;Comparing JVM Web Frameworks&amp;rdquo; by Matt Raible&lt;/a>. It was a really interesting presentation, and quite applicable to me at the moment because I&amp;rsquo;m trying to do decide an a new architecture and web framework for an application I&amp;rsquo;ve developed&amp;hellip; one that currently uses Primefaces.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One slide in particular caught my attention, referencing a link to a ThoughtWorks note about JSF:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;We continue to see teams run into trouble using JSF &amp;ndash; JavaServer Faces &amp;ndash; and are recommending you avoid this technology. Teams seem to choose JSF because it is a J2EE standard without really evaluating whether the programming model suits them. We think JSF is flawed because it tries to abstract away HTML, CSS and HTTP, exactly the reverse of what modern web frameworks do. JSF, like ASP.NET webforms, attempts to create statefulness on top of the stateless protocol HTTP and ends up causing a whole host of problems involving shared server-side state. We are aware of the improvements in JSF 2.0, but think the model is fundamentally broken. We recommend teams use simple frameworks and embrace and understand web technologies including HTTP, HTML and CSS.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/#/languages-and-frameworks/683">http://www.thoughtworks.com/radar/#/languages-and-frameworks/683&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This does kind of sum up an underlying uncomfortable feeling I&amp;rsquo;ve had with JSF and the few frameworks I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with (MyFaces and PrimeFaces). Primefaces in particular is great if you want to get something done quickly with a whole load of out-of-the-box components. But I don&amp;rsquo;t like the &amp;lsquo;statefulness on a stateless protocol (HTTP).&amp;rsquo; I&amp;rsquo;m drawn to use HTTP as it was intended (a stateless protocol) and move toward a REST based back end which I can plug in (and experiment with) any front end web framework I choose.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something else to keep in mind is what Rich Manalang calls the four principles of modern web development:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Designing for mobile first (even if you&amp;rsquo;re not building a mobile app)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Build only single page apps&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Create and use your own REST API (I really like this one - a work in progress for me)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;Sex sells&amp;rdquo; applies to web apps&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Installing Liquibase Extensions</title><link>https://awolski.com/installing-liquibase-extensions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/installing-liquibase-extensions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since version 3.1, support for &amp;lsquo;less common&amp;rsquo; databases has been removed from the core Liquibase distribution. This is documented Liquibase&amp;rsquo;s supported databases page. I&amp;rsquo;m working with a DB2i database, so I needed to work out how to install the &lt;a href="https://github.com/liquibase/liquibase-db2i">liquibase-db2i&lt;/a> extension. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any documentation anywhere, but I managed to nut out what was in the end a relatively trivial task&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Executing generateChangeLog via the command line looks something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-shell" data-lang="shell">liquibase --driver&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>com.ibm.as400.access.AS400JDBCDriver &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">&lt;/span> --classpath&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>jt400.jar &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">&lt;/span>--changeLogFile&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>file-to-export-to.xml &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">&lt;/span>--url&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;jdbc:as400://AS400X;libraries=LIBRARY;trace=false;naming=sql;extended dynamic=true;&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">&lt;/span>--username&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>blah --password&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>***** --logLevel&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>debug &lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">\
&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ae81ff">&lt;/span>--databaseClass&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>liquibase.ext.db2i.database.DB2iDatabase generateChangeLog
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Keeping a Primefaces MenuItem active</title><link>https://awolski.com/keeping-a-primefaces-menuitem-active/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/keeping-a-primefaces-menuitem-active/</guid><description>&lt;p>In an application I&amp;rsquo;m currently writing using Primefaces, I&amp;rsquo;m using a menu and individual menuItems to navigate to different pages. I wanted to keep the menuItem representing the current page to remain selected. For example, if the current page was /admin/users.xhtml, I wanted something like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://awolski.com/assets/img/2014-01-14-primefaces-menu-active.png" alt="Primefaces menu open">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After a little digging I found a neat little solution which only involved modifying the .xhtml file:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-xhtml" data-lang="xhtml">&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:menu&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">style&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;width:90%;&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:submenu&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">label&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Admin&amp;#34;&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:menuitem&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">value&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Users&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">outcome&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;users.xhtml&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">styleClass&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;#{view.viewId == &amp;#39;/admin/users.xhtml&amp;#39; ? &amp;#39;ui-state-active&amp;#39; : &amp;#39;&amp;#39;}&amp;#34;&lt;/span> /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:menuitem&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">value&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;Groups&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">outcome&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;groups.xhtml&amp;#34;&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">styleClass&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f92672">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#e6db74">&amp;#34;#{view.viewId == &amp;#39;/admin/groups.xhtml&amp;#39; ? &amp;#39;ui-state-active&amp;#39; : &amp;#39;&amp;#39;}&amp;#34;&lt;/span> /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:submenu&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/&lt;span style="color:#f92672">p:menu&lt;/span>&amp;gt;
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Hope this helps anyone looking for a similar solution.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monitoring energy use with Google Sheets, Forms and Apps Script</title><link>https://awolski.com/monitoring-energy-use-with-google-sheets-forms-and-apps-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/monitoring-energy-use-with-google-sheets-forms-and-apps-script/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently set up a nifty little Google Apps Script app using Sheets and Forms to track our electricity and gas consumption, and our solar generation. As Steve Howard - chief sustainability officer at IKEA - said in his TED talk Let&amp;rsquo;s go all-in on selling sustainability,&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;If you&amp;rsquo;re not measuring things, you don&amp;rsquo;t care, and you don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I want to know exactly how much energy we are using so that I can make efficiency adjustments over time, and know exactly how each one performs. How are you supposed to know why your bills are so high, or how to reduce them if you need to, when you don&amp;rsquo;t know what you&amp;rsquo;re actually using?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My requirements for the monitoring tool were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Something quick and easy to set up that allowed me to quickly enter meter readings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A calculation of daily consumption/production based on the day&amp;rsquo;s readings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If a reading was missed (i.e. we go away on holiday), daily consumption calculation to be averaged out over how many days readings were missed, not spiked on the one day the reading is done&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Calculation of the financial expense and income generated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pretty charts to visualise the data
Google Spreadsheets/Forms covered most of my requirements, and Apps Script gives me the flexibility and power to customise where Spreadsheets falls short.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>JavaOne 2013 - Decompose that WAR! Architecting for Adaptability, Scalability and Deployability</title><link>https://awolski.com/javaone-2013-decompose-that-war-architecting-for-adaptability-scalability-and-deployability/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/javaone-2013-decompose-that-war-architecting-for-adaptability-scalability-and-deployability/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night I watched the JavaOne 2013 session &lt;a href="http://parleys.com/play/525047b6e4b0c4f11ec5764b">Decompose that WAR! Architecting for Adaptability, Scalability and Deployability&lt;/a>. The presenter was Chris Richardson, the author of &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.co.uk/POJOs-Action-Developing-Applications-Lightweight/dp/1932394583">POJOs in Action&lt;/a>, and in the talk he discusses how very large applications bundled into a single war, what he calls monolithic applications, can give you more headaches than the benefits they provide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Liquibase against and existing database using LiquibaseServletListener</title><link>https://awolski.com/running-liquibase-against-and-existing-database-using-liquibaseservletlistener/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/running-liquibase-against-and-existing-database-using-liquibaseservletlistener/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently took on the task of integrating &lt;a href="http://www.liquibase.org/">Liquibase&lt;/a> into the project I&amp;rsquo;m working on at work. I&amp;rsquo;d played around with Liquibase before on small personal projects, but had never faced applying it to an existing, large and in-production database.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I ran into a few problems when using the LiquibaseServletListener after having previously run changelogSync via the command line. Basically, Liquibase was trying to execute the changesets in my changelog files even though they had already been executed during changelogSync. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand why.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Staying Focused on Performance with Evernote and IFTTT</title><link>https://awolski.com/staying-focused-on-performance-with-evernote-and-ifttt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/staying-focused-on-performance-with-evernote-and-ifttt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been one of those people who has all the best intentions at the start of a school, university or work year, to get organised, streamlined, and productive. I usually feel optimistic and determined&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s a clean slate, a fresh new page of a brand new notebook.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But as each week and month passes, I tend to lose focus and forget the goals I set out to achieve at the beginning of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In July this year I had a complete plan laid out about how I would smash my end of year performance review. I was determined to be uber-organised, perform so well and gather so much evidence that quantified my achievements. Come year end I would have the leverage to either push for a significant pay rise, or for the modified hours I want to experiment with (a four day work week).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tracking solar kWh with Google Spreadsheets &amp; IFTTT</title><link>https://awolski.com/tracking-solar-kwh-with-google-spreadsheets-ifttt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/tracking-solar-kwh-with-google-spreadsheets-ifttt/</guid><description>&lt;p>About a month ago we had solar panels installed. Sixteen panels in total, thirteen split over two sections of the roof and five on the garage, totalling a 4kW system. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered solar when we bought the house, but fortunately we have south-east and south-west facing sides of the house, and after a little research, solar turned out to be the best investment with the money available to invest.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I check the meter every now and again to see how many kWhs we&amp;rsquo;re producing. I&amp;rsquo;ve been surprised by the output on some days, and a little disappointed on others. One glorious October day we almost hit 16kWh. However on the frequent cloudy days here in the UK we&amp;rsquo;re barely able produce 1 or 2kWh. Two days ago I thought the system had stopped altogether.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Power searching in JIRA</title><link>https://awolski.com/power-searching-in-jira/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/power-searching-in-jira/</guid><description>&lt;p>I was promoted to Java Team Lead earlier this year, a role that comes with the responsibility of doing performance reviews biannually. In my first four months in the position I haven&amp;rsquo;t really worked closely with my team at all; they&amp;rsquo;re on completely different projects, and they are all just as busy as I am.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without knowing a great deal about the work they&amp;rsquo;ve been doing over the last 4-5 months, I needed to generate some metrics to see how each of my team members has performed against their Individual Performance Objectives. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure how I was going to do this, until I delved into the world &lt;a href="https://confluence.atlassian.com/display/JIRA/Advanced+Searching">advanced searching in JIRA with JQL&lt;/a> (Jira Query Language).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://awolski.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Atomic Habits - James Clear</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Atomic Habits is a must read for anyone struggling to maintain good habits or break bad ones. It reinforces the idea that success comes from repetition. You have to show up day-in, day-out, regardless of whether you feel like it or not. The book drives this point home and outlines practical ways to make it more likely you do so, such as environment design and habit stacking. I took so many notes and gained so much from this read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://awolski.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/contact/</guid><description>I can be contacted via email at tony@awolski.com.</description></item><item><title>Conveyancing Quote System</title><link>https://awolski.com/cqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/cqs/</guid><description>In 2012 I built a system for a law firm in Cardiff to streamline the process of creating conveyancing quotes. It has been in production use ever since.
The system allows the firm to rapidly take details of clients who are purchasing or selling a property, and automatically calculates fees such as stamp duty and land taxes. Quotes are calculated on the fly so agents can give clients accurate, real-time view of what the purchase or sale will cost.</description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism - Cal Newport</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/digital-minimalism/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another timely and compelling piece by Cal Newport. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason the author is one of only two writers&amp;rsquo; blogs to which I&amp;rsquo;m subscribed. Lots of great research into how our inability to disconnect affects our mental health, our ability to concentrate, and the connection we feel to the community around us.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eat That Frog! - Brian Tracy</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/eatthatfrog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/eatthatfrog/</guid><description>&lt;p>A good book which emphasises the power of tackling your most important tasks and projects first, and focusing single mindedly on one task or project at a time to achive ultimate success in life. Eat That Frog! is not a long read, but did a good job of emphasising good habits I&amp;rsquo;ve read about in other books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ReWork - Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/rework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/rework/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book twice now. I love books that offer &amp;lsquo;uncommon sense&amp;rsquo; approaches; alternative ways to look at and solve problems. This is one of them. In ReWork, Jason Fried and DHH debunk the common view that you have to grow and get big to be successful. You don&amp;rsquo;t. You can stay small and build the business you want, the way you want, and ignore the &amp;lsquo;common nonsense&amp;rsquo;. The thoughts in this book have shown me an alternative blueprint for creating a business. They&amp;rsquo;re thoughts that I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit again and again in the future. I highly recommend this book, and many of their blog posts on &lt;a href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/">Signal v. Noise&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>So Good They Can't Ignore You - Cal Newport</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bullet Journal Method - Ryder Carrol</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-bullet-journal-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-bullet-journal-method/</guid><description>&lt;p>What a fantastic resource and book! I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling for years, and I get immense value from observing my thoughts, writing about what&amp;rsquo;s bothering me or a problem I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on. But there&amp;rsquo;s always been a disconnect between what I discover through journaling and the actions that arise from it. My organisational methods have gone through so many iterations and digital tools over the years, each promising so much but ultimately failing in one way or another, forcing me to abandon them. This book and method provide a compelling answer to my issues with digital organisation. The Bullet Journal Method not only outlines the process of Bullet Journaling, but explains why it is such an effective method. Disconnecting from online distractions and information overload, giving yourself time and space to think, reflect and plan. The Bullet Journal method has completely changed my life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Millionaire Next Door - Thomas J. Stanley, William D. Danko</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-millionaire-next-door/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-millionaire-next-door/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Simple Path to Wealth - JL Collins</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-simple-path-to-wealth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-simple-path-to-wealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>JL Collins lays out a straightforward guide to reaching financial independence in &lt;em>The Simple Path to Wealth&lt;/em>. There really is no excuse to delay thinking about your financial future, and as the author explains, investing can be as simple as sticking your money in one low cost index fund. This is a fantastic resource for those of us who prefer to let someone else think about money and investing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The War of Art - Steven Pressfield</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-war-of-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-war-of-art/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Walden; Or, Life in The Woods - David Henry Thoreau</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/walden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/walden/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my all time favourite books, and one that I will revisit often in my life. Ipsum lorem dolor. , its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What I’m doing now</title><link>https://awolski.com/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/now/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on my new business yvant.io. Founded in March 2020 with my co-founder Iván Perdomo, Yvant is a DevOps consultancy that helps its clients run on less, produce more and deliver faster. We&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with setup activities and working with our first client. Things are going well and I&amp;rsquo;m excited for what&amp;rsquo;s in store, not only for us but also for our clients.
I have also become a teacher (unofficially).</description></item><item><title>Work</title><link>https://awolski.com/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/work/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software/devops engineer with twenty years of experience in a range of industries. I love learning and solving complex problems with simple solutions. I started out as a Java developer but gravitated towards continuous delivery, process improvement and automation (apparently now called DevOps). I focus on getting code into production as fast and safe as possible.
Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with AWS, Terraform, Docker, Node.js, Groovy and MySQL. However, over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve built up experience with a wide array of cloud platforms, programming languages, automation tools and practices.</description></item><item><title>Your Money or Your Life - Vicki Robin &amp; Joe Dominguez</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/your-money-or-your-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/your-money-or-your-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m working my way through the steps in this book, so will withhold my thoughts until I&amp;rsquo;ve completed them. However this is one of my favourites, enough so that I&amp;rsquo;ve read it twice. It lays out a program to re-evaluate our relationship with money, how we acquire it, how we spend it, and how we think about it. The program requires a significant investment in time and energy, but promises so much. Watch this space.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>