<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Book notes on Tony Wolski</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/</link><description>Recent content in Book notes on Tony Wolski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://awolski.com/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atomic Habits - James Clear</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/atomic-habits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/atomic-habits/</guid><description>&lt;p>Atomic Habits is a must read for anyone struggling to maintain good habits or break bad ones. It reinforces the idea that success comes from repetition. You have to show up day-in, day-out, regardless of whether you feel like it or not. The book drives this point home and outlines practical ways to make it more likely you do so, such as environment design and habit stacking. I took so many notes and gained so much from this read.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Digital Minimalism - Cal Newport</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/digital-minimalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/digital-minimalism/</guid><description>&lt;p>Another timely and compelling piece by Cal Newport. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason the author is one of only two writers' blogs to which I&amp;rsquo;m subscribed. Lots of great research into how our inability to disconnect affects our mental health, our ability to concentrate, and the connection we feel to the community around us.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Eat That Frog! - Brian Tracy</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/eatthatfrog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/eatthatfrog/</guid><description>&lt;p>A good book which emphasises the power of tackling your most important tasks and projects first, and focusing single mindedly on one task or project at a time to achive ultimate success in life. Eat That Frog! is not a long read, but did a good job of emphasising good habits I&amp;rsquo;ve read about in other books.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ReWork - Jason Fried and David Heinemeier Hansson</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/rework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/rework/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve read this book twice now. I love books that offer &amp;lsquo;uncommon sense&amp;rsquo; approaches; alternative ways to look at and solve problems. This is one of them. In ReWork, Jason Fried and DHH debunk the common view that you have to grow and get big to be successful. You don&amp;rsquo;t. You can stay small and build the business you want, the way you want, and ignore the &amp;lsquo;common nonsense&amp;rsquo;. The thoughts in this book have shown me an alternative blueprint for creating a business. They&amp;rsquo;re thoughts that I&amp;rsquo;ll revisit again and again in the future. I highly recommend this book, and many of their blog posts on &lt;a href="https://m.signalvnoise.com/">Signal v. Noise&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>So Good They Can't Ignore You - Cal Newport</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/so-good-they-cant-ignore-you/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bullet Journal Method - Ryder Carrol</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-bullet-journal-method/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-bullet-journal-method/</guid><description>&lt;p>What a fantastic resource and book! I&amp;rsquo;ve been journaling for years, and I get immense value from observing my thoughts, writing about what&amp;rsquo;s bothering me or a problem I&amp;rsquo;m stuck on. But there&amp;rsquo;s always been a disconnect between what I discover through journaling and the actions that arise from it. My organisational methods have gone through so many iterations and digital tools over the years, each promising so much but ultimately failing in one way or another, forcing me to abandon them. This book and method provide a compelling answer to my issues with digital organisation. The Bullet Journal Method not only outlines the process of Bullet Journaling, but explains why it is such an effective method. Disconnecting from online distractions and information overload, giving yourself time and space to think, reflect and plan. The Bullet Journal method has completely changed my life.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Millionaire Next Door - Thomas J. Stanley, William D. Danko</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-millionaire-next-door/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-millionaire-next-door/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Simple Path to Wealth - JL Collins</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-simple-path-to-wealth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-simple-path-to-wealth/</guid><description>&lt;p>JL Collins lays out a straightforward guide to reaching financial independence in &lt;em>The Simple Path to Wealth&lt;/em>. There really is no excuse to delay thinking about your financial future, and as the author explains, investing can be as simple as sticking your money in one low cost index fund. This is a fantastic resource for those of us who prefer to let someone else think about money and investing.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The War of Art - Steven Pressfield</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/the-war-of-art/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/the-war-of-art/</guid><description>&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Book notes coming in September 2019&amp;hellip;&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Walden; Or, Life in The Woods - David Henry Thoreau</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/walden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/walden/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of my all time favourite books, and one that I will revisit often in my life. Ipsum lorem dolor. , its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past, its Augean stables never cleansed, and one hundred acres of land, tillage, mowing past&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Your Money or Your Life - Vicki Robin &amp; Joe Dominguez</title><link>https://awolski.com/books/your-money-or-your-life/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/books/your-money-or-your-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m working my way through the steps in this book, so will withhold my thoughts until I&amp;rsquo;ve completed them. However this is one of my favourites, enough so that I&amp;rsquo;ve read it twice. It lays out a program to re-evaluate our relationship with money, how we acquire it, how we spend it, and how we think about it. The program requires a significant investment in time and energy, but promises so much. Watch this space.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>