<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Tony Wolski</title><link>https://awolski.com/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Tony Wolski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:39:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awolski.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ten percent</title><link>https://awolski.com/10pc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:39:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/10pc/</guid><description>Each month I give 10% of my earnings (income not profit) to causes that benefit others and improve our long-term future.
I select charities recommended by organisations such as Effective Altruism and Give Well to maximise my donations and turn them into real action.
This page exists not to boast, but to hold myself accountable. It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation intention.
Why? I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly fortunate. I was born in a safe and prosperous country, raised by loving parents, siblings, extended family and friends.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://awolski.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://awolski.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/contact/</guid><description>I can be contacted via email at tony@awolski.com.
My PGP key is here or on keybase.io/awolski.</description></item><item><title>What I’m doing now</title><link>https://awolski.com/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/now/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on and in my new business Yvant, a DevOps consultancy that helps its clients run on less, produce more and deliver faster. We&amp;rsquo;re almost finished our first significant project: an API, surrounding AWS infrastructure and CI/CD pipelines.
It has been a really busy time trying to juggle the new workload whilst at the same time home-schooling the kids, but now it&amp;rsquo;s school holidays I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to some pockets of downtime with the family before school goes back and work ramps up.</description></item><item><title>Work</title><link>https://awolski.com/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awolski.com/work/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software/devops engineer with twenty years of experience, currently available for new projects via my company Yvant.
I started out as a Java developer but gravitated towards continuous delivery, process improvement and automation (apparently now called DevOps). I focus on getting code into production as fast and safe as possible.
Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with AWS, Terraform, Docker, Node.js, Groovy and MySQL. However, over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve built up experience with a wide array of cloud platforms, programming languages, automation tools and practices.</description></item></channel></rss>