<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pages on Tony Wolski</title><link>https://awol.ski/pages/</link><description>Recent content in Pages on Tony Wolski</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:39:33 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://awol.ski/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ten percent</title><link>https://awol.ski/10pc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2020 05:39:33 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://awol.ski/10pc/</guid><description>Each month I give 10% of my earnings (income not profit) to causes that benefit others and improve our long-term future.
I select charities recommended by organisations such as Effective Altruism and Give Well to maximise my donations and turn them into real action.
This page exists not to boast, but to hold myself accountable. It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation intention.
Why? I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly fortunate. I was born in a safe and prosperous country, raised by loving parents, siblings, extended family and friends.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://awol.ski/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awol.ski/about/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://awol.ski/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awol.ski/contact/</guid><description>I can be contacted via email at tony@awolski.com.
GPG: 0x72CA03529FF0C81C.</description></item><item><title>What I’m doing now</title><link>https://awol.ski/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awol.ski/now/</guid><description>The UK is back in strict lockdown due to soaring Covid cases and, sadly, rising deaths. Like so many others I&amp;rsquo;m juggling home school and work. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to keep safe and at the same time remain connected with friends and family.
I&amp;rsquo;m working on turning Yvant into a Co-op.
I&amp;rsquo;m reading Bodyguard of Lies by Anthony Cave Brown, a behemoth of a book, and certainly the largest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever read.</description></item><item><title>Work</title><link>https://awol.ski/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://awol.ski/work/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a software/devops engineer with twenty years of experience, currently available for new projects via my company Yvant.
I started out as a Java developer but gravitated towards continuous delivery, process improvement and automation (apparently now called DevOps). I focus on getting code into production as fast and safe as possible.
Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with AWS, Terraform, Docker, Node.js, Groovy and MySQL. However, over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve built up experience with a wide array of cloud platforms, programming languages, automation tools and practices.</description></item></channel></rss>